TheMarkusGuy
Markus computer entertainment
MarkuStation 2 (MTM)
TrackMania - Frozen tracks
Track #1
SNOWin
Snow city
Track #3
Put on the boots
Track #4
Frozen paradise
Track #5
Frozen beach
Track #6
Coast in Norway
Track #7
ForestMania
Track #8
"The trap"
Track #9
Snow stunts and jumping
Track #10
Snow track
Track #11
Polaris
Track #12
Black track (Title of the world 10)
The end
Edited by:
Markus Maal
Music:
Tracks by:
Markus Maal
Software used:
TrackMania United Forever (Tracks, Recording)
Sony Vegas Pro 11.0 (Editing)
X-Vid MPEG4 codec (Encoding format)
paint.NET (Image manipulation)
Created for:
TheMarkusGuy
(c) 2019 Markuse videod productions
Watch more:
More channels
Subtitles by: Markus Maal (MarkusTegelane/TheMarkusGuy)