Hello, people!
I want to check if I'm recording...
Yup, I'm recording right now and push-to-talk is working
Everything is correct
For those who don't know... I have a Minecraft blog and in this amazing world called "hey, survive"
I have beaten that dragon
Now... I want to beat this dragon again.
Lets see what happens
And I have a strong wind around here, hope that doesn't affect the recording. Lets start with the video.
So first, lets prepare for everything
Then we'll go to the nether and...
...go into the end portal and respawn the dragon
To collect a few bottles of dragon's breath... and to get some XP
Because I really, really need XP
But lets start
And we have a lot of rockets to fly with an elytra
and to destroy those... amazing... end crystals
which in fact, we collected, some time ago, when we were in the nether
we have 4 amazing end crystals
wow
We'll obviously be taking some end crystals with us, in order to respawn the end dragon
we'll also be taking a water bucket to avoid problems... with the ender men
or rather to solve problems with ender men
to AVOID problems...
we have this wonderful thing called "carved pumpkin"
wow
I'm looking really good right now, people
we are wearing a wonderful pumpkin, we are wearing a sword
we have a cool chip, which i haven't shown you, but we do have a chip... i mean shield
and we are wearing a wonderful pumpkin
of course we'll need our blast resistance... obviously
hmmm... what else could we take with us? bow? bow will stay here...
or actually we'll take the bow with us.. we don't need rotten flesh... we'll take chorus fruit, just in case... we'll take one ender pearl also
we'll take empty bottles with us, to collect dragon's breath
we really take it with us... I'll also be looking at other potions I could bring to the end...
where did it go?
nice
a little lesson here: use your dshield [woosh]
actually use your shield, if you can
*sigh*
*explosion*
don't ask how the chicken go into the nether
oh hello... speed II...
suddenly in a random chest i don't know about
the only way i can retrieve this potion again is using the road in the nether
now comes the hard decision time: what will I take and what will I leave here?
i would like to build a little shelther in the end... in case things turn for the worst, so i may want to take a few blocks
oh, and we have empty glass bottles here..
people, we're officially in the end
endermen: *sup* *hey* *lokfoteaay*
as you can see, there are a lot of these... ender men... and I can't look at them, unless I'm wwaring a pumpkin on my head
but if i'm wearing a pumpkin, i either have to use the third person perpective or see poke through the holes on the pumpkin
everybody is looking at me, being like: "what are you doing herer?" :D
my display was on minimum brightness owow
these ender men are agrovated by the dragon
you're winner
people, we beat the dragon... roughly, but we did
and that's that... we got 17 levels... and a lot of dragon's breath
I'll unequip this silly pumpkin to see something
ok, so that is where the second end gateway is.
and now we have about... 127 dragon's breath, which we can use to make different kinds of potions
yeah, we beat the dragon second time and that's that
wth why are there so many mobs? like, why did so many zombies just spawn? jc
*inhales* Lets see...
wow, why were there so many zombies all of a sudden? no idea. wth
they're fine
that probably explains why so many zombies spawned, they all wanted to destroy the villagers
but thanks to iron golems, villagers were saved
and we have 4 ender eyes right now (?)
And that was it for the video. Thank you for watching! Have a nice day! Hope I didn't forget to start recording, that would have been a good joke...
but I'll stop recording NOW