Markus computer entertainment
Hello people! Today I am showcasing a new version of Windows that you have never seen before!
I got exclusive access to the beta version for the beta version of Windows 13!
And we're on the desktop!
On a brand new desktop!
With a brand new background image!
As you can see, the new wallpaper has a very minimalistic design.
And also a new taskbar
New, as you can see. There's still access to the start menu
Settings icon, application store
File manager
VLC
Terminal, Pinta...
I mean Paint, that's absolutely just paint and not some other program!
notepad, and everything else
And a brand new Microsoft's office suite!
Such as Michaelsoft Letter, Michaelsoft Isuc, and Michaelsoft Weakpoint!
I can't believe it! It's a brand new and very unique version of Windows!
Something completely brand new, something nobody has seen before!
Lets start with the file manager!
As you can see, there are still rounded corners.
But as a brand new feature, there's now an option to split the current folder you're on!
You may be wondering, why is that useful? Let me show you!
First of all, here's one folder...
Let me insert a storage medium that actually contains some files.
And every time you insert a new USB device, Windows asks whether or not you want to connect it! Unbelieveably awesome!
So, if you have a faulty drive, it doesn't get too much stress reading data unless you say to insert it.
You can probably also run your .EXE file....
Dialog box: What would you like to do with this file?
We can go to a folder, such as music...
and then we CANN
And as you can see, we support... Windows supports multiple tabs in the file manager, which means...
that browsing your files is... You don't have to open 10 windows and search for which one you want to use.
So, that was My Computer. One more thing... If we change the path here...
Then you can see that Windows now uses a brand new file path system!
There is no C:\ drive anymore! Everything starts from /!
For example, our user folder is /home/markus
So, this is our C:\ folder, a.k.a. the / folder
In case you think I'm joking. (shows that path is indeed "/")
You may be asking, where's my D: drive, where's my E: drive, where's my F: drive... well
The answer is that they are now located at...
I'm pretty sure it was the /media folder...
Yup, here's my thumbdrive. We can explore it.
This is a brand new photos app.
It starts up really fast and there is no other unneeded carp!
This is Michaelsoft Letter! Microsoft decided to rename the programs on their office suite.
It's really similar in terms of feature set to Microsoft Word (as it should be)
Not much has changed, other than the design and layout of things.
This is Michaelsoft Isuc
And this is Michaelsoft Weakpoint!
Which you can use to make amazing presentations, where your weak points never get heard!
Maybe you saw another new thing.
If we open updates
Everyone knows that Windows updates are really annoying! They tend to install themselves automatically without your permission...
But not anymore! Because Windows 13 eliminates this problem completely!
Wait, is it going to install Windows 14 here?
Yeah, absolutely...
It's probably Windows 13.1 or something, but I don't care right now!
And as you saw, it was really easy to postpone updates, no need to install them right away when you don't want to!
The settings app has also been updated, so...
It looks a bit like Windows 11 settings app, but it isn't that...
What is a KDE neon?
This is the new paint app!
As you can see, it's still possible to dra...
You can still draw!
But in addition to drawing stuff... [that sound]
There's layers, so that we can add new layers!
That is one of the things people have always asked Microsoft to do, but they've never actually done it!
There's layers in Paint now! That's unbelievable!
Like in every other fuggin picture editing program...
Next up... I accidentally opened VLC media player! YAY!
Let me tell you, this isn't Lunix, okay... some smart people may point out this is just Lunix, but it isn't!
this is 100% Windows 13
Next up we open the command line, which looks totally awesome!
This totally isn't just Lunix...
I can confirm this to you...
This isn't Lunix, it's Linux...
Happy April 1st!