Presents...
Markus'
Computer
Entertainment
Markus'
Computer
Entertainment
Licensed by:
Markus' entertainment Estonia
©MME
Markus' computer entertainment
FreeBSD
He-he-hello... (repeated at different speeds)
FreeBSD, FreeBSD
What can I say about FreeBSD?
We have two images, in case I can't figure out how to install it properly.
But lets see what's going to happen.
[types] FreeBSD
64-bit
ok
fork it, it's the right size
and boop, boop, boop, boop, boop, boop...
we obviously are going to need more cores
I'll use... 3 or 4 cores?
lets do 90%, what does it say?
Okay, I understand what that means. PAE/NX I will not enable unless I have to.
I won't mess around with that.
I'll set it to "Bridged adapter"
Of course it asks what it should boot, so...
FreeBSD it is
okay, lets see what happens...
ok
FreeBSD, lets see what this is.
[ reads stuff on screen ]
so we have an interesting installer
we have Shell, which I assume is the command line.
Live CD, which allows us to test it or Install. Lets try installing it.
(sigh) let's see how usable it is
wait, test Estonian keymap?
types "this little moulder gets to jump on the train" in Estonian (basically the Estonian version of the quick brown fox sentence, but only for testing specific Estonian letters)
the letter Õ doesn't work, but it's fine
yes, that was definitely the biggest problem lol
because...
continue with this
So what do we want to install?
Lets install everything. I don't know. In case we need it.
[ read stuff on screen ]
okay, lets try the automatic setup
then
layout
this
everything seems fine
okay, seems fine (2x)
[ reads stuff on screen ]
breaks crash dumps
woawoawoawoawoawoa
we are experiencing technical difficulties
interesting question.. why...?
because why not
why would you want to mirror swap partitions? is it to make the system like ultra stable or something?
like
what
INSTALL
we have software RAID options
we'll do No Redundancy
[ reads the warning ]
YES
okay
[timelapse music, definitely not from someone else]
what
Select a password for the system management account
okay
we'll use a """very secure""" password
(the password is 123abc)
(giggle)
okay network interface
Would you like to configure
Yes
okay, lets see...
lets see, lets see
Would you like to configure IPv6
YES
Would you like stateless... YES
Lets see if it lets me automatically test it
Europe (the continent)
Estonia
Does the abbreviation EEST look
YES
I'm going to skip through that
[ reads stuff on the screen ]
[ reads even more stuff on the screen ]
I can't see the whole line!
Hide processes running in jails
is this a sandbox thing or what?
Sendmail service, to be honest I don't really care about that
lets see, it's not like I care about this system at all
nyeyah
Login group
lets say users
[ fan spin ]
nah
okay
I don't care
Change root password
Apply configuration
[ reads the text on screen ]
reboot
Will it eject the CD?
No
BIOS drive C: is disk0
Boot... ehm... Enter
okay
trying to log in with an account I didn't
event make :D
cool
we have man, which helps us get things done
what commands do we have available?
yay
there's xorg and stuff
to less
In the next part of this video, I tried to install a display server, session manager and
a desktop environment.
I'm just hoping... oh.
we have xorg
yay, we have xorg, we have a working window system
Testing X.org with the default window manager:
but we don't have additions
installing xfce
Does Firefox work? Yup, Firework indeed works. So, this is Firefox in FreeBSD.
Installing GDM
install GDM
That's not a good sign.
And we're on the same... oh my god.
okay... session man...
If there are any FreeBSD or GDM experts watching, then you can explain in the
comments, what you think went wrong here. My hypothesis is that using the
root account only wasn't the best idea.
yay
okay
YAY, we got something to work!
Okay, display. I want to...
yay
File manager, which is Thunar, if I'm not mistaken...
Yup.
The default theme for xfce here isn't the worst thing in the world.
Greybird, Greybird-dark
This is our... this is xfce
...in FreeBSD.
And as you can see, FreeBSD is a total pain, but it is usable.
What is the built-in browser?
Oh, it's just using Firefox.
Yes, make Firefox my default browser
Can we watch YouTube, that's the question..
No
We can't, because we're not connected to the internet.
we are experiencing technical difficulties
because I'm dumb
FreeBSD, as you can see, is able to play YouTube videos, even if there are no video drivers.
oh, okay
This video is 60fps, but this right here obviously isn't 60 frames per second.
As you saw, it's able to play HD video, but not 60 fps HD video.
Neofetch, does it have neofetch? Yes it does.
Just curious what it looks like.
Here's package installation, for those who are curious.
BOOM, so yeah, that's FreeBSD.
So, FreeBSD is infinitely customizable and configurable for your
specific usesasif
specific useless case
useless
use case
What do you want it for?
Of course, as your primary operating system, it's possible to use FreeBSD, but...
Lets just say it's not recommended.
Because, as you saw, you have to put in a lot of effort to even get to any kind of a desktop.
If you really want to, you can use it...
But if you're the person that wants everything to just work out of the box, FreeBSD isn't meant for you.
The End
Created by
Software:
kdenlive (video editing)
VirtualBox (virtualization)
FreeBSD, Manjaro Linux, Windows 11 (OSes)
OBS Studio (screen capture)
paint.NET (thumbnail)
Google Chrome (uploading)
Aegisub (subtitles)
Music:
Created for channel
Thank you for watching!
© 2022 Markus' Videos Productions
Watch more
Other channels