presents...
Markus
Computer
Entertainment
Licensed by
Markus entertainment Estonia
©MME
Welcome!
In many of these Markus computer entertainment videos, I've shown a phone that boots several different operating systems,
which includes Ubuntu Touch, Sailfish, Android versions, or whatever.
Even Firefox OS
Now, the question is: how?
In some videos, I've been able to boot multiple operating systems within a single smart phone.
And in this video, I am going to show you the tool that lets you do that, which allows you to multiboot operating systems.
This is Multirom by Tassadar
We'll restart the device, and I'll adjust the brightness first...
As you can see, Multirom, which allows us to boot multiple operating systems, lets us choose what to boot from a list.
In Multirom, there's a primary ROM and secondary ROMs.
If you're tech savvy, you might say that these are not ROMs, these are operating systems and
that's a good point, but what you need to keep in mind is that the community has always referred to these custom firmware modifications as ROMs.
Everyone's calling them ROMs.
So, deal with it.
There are three tabs. INTERNAL lets you boot OSs from internal storage.
EXTERNAL is interesting... If you have a USB device and you want to boot OSs from it, then it's possible.
And as it says here, once you insert the USB it's mounted and bootable OSs are detected automatically.
(obviously only when you add these OSs to the USB drive using Multirom)
Next tab: MISC.
First option: COPY LOG TO /SDCARD, allows you to copy a log.
and yes, the log is saved to that location
Next options: reboot, allow you to reboot your device in several different ways and SHUTDOWN shuts down the device.
I can demo these later.
But here are some themes you can apply.
Default (I wanted to say Orange, sorry 'bout that)
Default
Red
Blue
Purple
Green
Dark theme
and the Darkest theme, where the background is completely black.
and another interesting feature here is...
And yes, it's pretty hard, but yes, that's an easter egg.
I won. How is that possible?
And you can press the power button to return to the main menu.
I'll just boot the primary operating system as a demonstration.
Which in this phone is CyanogenMod 12
If we press it again
again (5x)
Then it'll boot up.
And our device will boot into the operating system.
And yes, I'll be back in a moment.
As you can see, we've booted into an operating system.
And this is the OS, where we have an app called "MultiROM manager" installed.
Which allows you to manage these operating systems.
So, if we start it up here...
...then you see that This device is not officially supported.
I really wanted to use an officially supported device, but I was unable to do it.
Because that device still has battery problems.
But what we can do is check out what is available to us.
MultiROM has three components:
1. MultiROM itself, which shows us the menu, which allows us to choose an OS and stuff
2. Recovery, which we'll talk about later in this video.
3. Kernel, which has the kexec hardboot patch
And if we look at the Manage ROMs menu...
Then we'll see all of our ROMs. We can rename them.
And we can also change the icons.
These are the built-in icons.
For KitKat we can use... maybe this one...
We can change the icon and if we reboot, it'll be applied.
And while this is the OmniROM icon, nobody really cares.
I just wanted to demonstrate a point.
Next. We can also reboot and we have options.
If this were an officially supported device, we could also install Ubuntu Touch from here, but...
Yeah, this device is unsupported, we can't do it.
We also have an autoboot function. If we press CANCEL, it goes away.
And as you can see, our icon has been applied successfully.
I'll now just boot Firefox OS
Because why not.
Then you'll notice something interesting.
The device reboots.
If you noticed what happened with the primary ROM, it just booted into the OS without rebooting the device.
Maybe you'll notice something funny in Firefox OS...
We have this interesting thing going across the screen, but if we lock and unlock the device, it's gone.
I don't know why this trick works, but it does anyway.
Firefox, a few years ago, closed the Marketplace, which means that it doesn't work anymore.
But if we open the browser, it actually does work.
I have tried a few test sites already. And it does indeed work.
check the card!
I made a whole video about Firefox OS, where I demonstrated the Marketplace back when it did work.
So, you should watch that video.
If we now reboot the device.
Then our OS will shut down and we'll be brought back to the MultiROM menu.
One thing I forgot... Okay I'll first show what happens when we tap REBOOT TO BOOTLOADER.
Yeah, we get this menu.
It's a mode where you can flash recoveries, operating systems, and other stuff, but...
Speaking of recovery, there's one thing I haven't shown you yet. REBOOT TO RECOVERY
MultiROM uses its very own recovery environment, where you can flash ROMs.
So, it's a customized version of TeamWin Recovery Project (TWRP)
Which works like the normal version of TWRP, but... if you tap here then BOOM, MultiROM - Main Menu
If you tap the hamburger menu on the main screen, you'll get to MultiROM's own menu here.
We have 6 options
[ reads them out ]
So what do these options do?
First, Add ROM allows you to add operating systems.
List ROMs lists all of the OSs you have installed.
We see the same thing to what we saw in MultiROM manager, apart from the icons.
And if we click on one of them, we'll see a bunch of options specific to the ROM.
First of all Delete, which erases the ROM from the device
Wipe Data, which erases user data.
Remove Boot.img, which... probably removes the kernel, but I have no idea why would you want to do this.
Set Radio.img
Sideloading through ADB, if you want to install something directly from your computer.
Run Restorecon, which... I am not sure what that does.
Rename, which allows us to rename
Backup allows you to make a backup.
Wipe Dalvik and Wipe Cache, allow you to delete different types of cached data.
Install Zip, allows you to install gapps, root, and do other stuff.
Inject boot.img allows you to flash your own boot.img and patch it with MultiROM, basically.
Inject boot sector. Sometimes you might lose the MultiROM menu, this option allows you to restore it.
Settings, are basically MultiROM settings.
and Swap ROMs, we'll talk about it later.
Settings
We can rename internal ROM, as well as hide it, if we never want to boot to it.
Force us... maybe it's software based screen drawing mode, I don't know.
Enable advanced kernel logging + history, maybe it's useful for debugging and troubleshooting.
Enable No-KEXEC Workaround, that one is useful if your kernel doesn't have the kexec hardboot patch.
Animation duration, screen brightness.
AUTOBOOT - we can choose, which OS to boot automatically.
We can disable autoboot, which will just show the MultiROM menu.
Keypress based boot, which allows us to hold down certain buttons to show the menu, otherwise boot into the default operating system.
And time based boot, which shows the menu, but delays, which is what we were using.
We'll disable autoboot to demonstrate that these settings are applied automatically.
If we choose Add ROM
We can install an Android system or use MultiROM installer file, which lets us install other operating systems.
Next, we can choose what source we should use for the OS.
We can choose between Zip file, which is what we showed earlier.
Backup, which is interesting, because you can restore a TWRP backup and use it as a secondary OS.
And sideloading through ADB, if you want to install something directly from your computer.
So, we'll choose Zip file.
And we'll choose downloads...
...and Paranoid Android, we'll try to install it.
I haven't tried to install it before this video, lets see what happens with this ZIP file.
We'll select Reboot system and try to boot this OS.
As you can see, we'll appear into this menu just like that.
As you can see, it's using a very ugly name, as well as a general icon. I'll show you how to change it later.
But just to test if it works... lets see if it boots.
Okay, the device is rebooting...
And lets see if it kernel panics or boots into the system.
Okay...
Oh, the screen turned off, the device rebooted....
I have a feeling this isn't going to work, which is unfortunate, but...
Yes, so as you can see, the compatibility isn't perfect.
In order to show you how this works, we'll show you a folder called multirom in the internal memory.
And if you select a folder called roms, then here are all of these systems.
So, the first thing that happens when you boot a ROM is that boot.img gets flashed, which has been injected with MultiROM.
And then your device is rebooted.
In order to use the new kernel, that's why the device reboots.
But you may be asking: why does it go back to MultiROM once the device is rebooted, even after we flashed a new kernel?
The reason is simple: because it flashes back to kernel, because it's been flashed and it can do that.
If we didn't patch it, we would just keep booting back into the MultiROM menu again and again and again....
Which isn't obviously what we want to do.
One interesting feature I didn't show was Swap ROMs...
Here we can swap the primary ROM with a secondary ROM. And here we have everything we can swap with it.
I don't know if I would ever do this, probably not.
So yeah.
Duplicate secondary ROM, that's probably the safest thing we can do.
Altough, I really don't want to do anything right now.
But the idea is that you can either Swap your primary ROM with one of the secondary ones...
Copy primary ROM to one of the secondaries
Or copy secondary ROM to another secondary ROM.
Basically, you can copy, paste, move, whatever.
And you can choose a name.
I also want to show you another thing that can happen when your OS doesn't want to boot.
So, if I choose Android Kitkat here...
Which I hoped would work...
Then the device does reboot, you maybe hopeful that it's going to work, but boom.
kernel panic YAY
I want to show you one more operating system that is also based on Android, but that does actually start up.
That would be MIUI 8.
I was planning to make a Markus computer entertainment video about MIUI 8, but I never did for some reason. I don't know why, but I didn't.
WOW, it's working so well in this phone.
Another PIN code...
YAY
As you can see, a completely different system.
Okay, this is interesting.
And it's based on Android Marshmallow.
I don't know why it's so slow right now.
It was so much faster before.
WOW (2x)
Wow, applause!
It was such a wonderful gameplay right here.
Another interesting thing - there's a built-in Play Store app. I didn't install it, it was just included with the OS.
You can also download themes and stuff like that.
But I've noticed it requires a Xiaomi account, like wha? why?
Like why?
Why? Why do I need an account to install themes?
Like, what the hell?
We can also boot into recovery and fastboot really quickly.
Rebooting...
So, this was MultiROM. So yeah, this was a kind of behind the scenes overview.
Like what's happening behin... behin.. behind.. the scenes like?
Whatever.
Behind the scenes. I sayed behind the scenes too much. Why did I say behind the scenes?
Maybe I'll show you one more thing....
Yup, remember how we had a ROM with a very ugly name and icon?
Now, an interesting way to fix it...
You can rename it.
As you can see, I renamed it.
We can also change the icon.
And... boom, we have the Paranoid Android icon.
And the very last thing I want to show you is how to delete ROMs.
If we try to delete it, it notifies us and says "hey, you sure you know what you're doing?".
Lets tap ERASE, it thinks about it for a moment, and then it's gone.
Pretty quickly and efficiently.
And yes, MultiROM Manager requires root access.
I didn't use MultiROM in my Sailfish OS video, for example.
Just because I couldn't get it to work.
And I also didn't use it in my Android Oreo overview, for the same reason.
Because the latest OS MultiROM officially supports is Android 6.0 Marshmallow.
Which is also why I was able to get the MIUI ROM working.
But...
It should support Android KitKat, so I don't know why I wasn't able to get that working...
I really don't know.
That's it. And...
Thank you for watching this video!
Watch more
Other channels