This computer is incompatible with Windows 11. But I started the installer.
Let's click "Next"
And if we click install now...
What happens?
We're being asked for a product key. Let's just say...
...nope
Let's choose Windows 11 Pro for example
And let's see what happens next
quack, quack, quaaack
And this is where most people would say, okay my computer is incompatible, I give up. But not me.
Okay, I now created these registry values, let's see what happens...
Let's close this down...
and BOOP
WOW
laughter
okay
BOOP
And as you can see, it's installing Windows
Almost done
96%!
wow
Are we nearing the end of installation?
98 percent
Now... does it restart?
I wonder
oh my god
laughter
I wasn't expecting this to be that simple.
Black screen
Restart, okay.
oh my god
oh my god (2x)
nonononononoo
nononononoo
wow
white screen
oh my god, this...
...it's working really well, as you can see
that framerate
what the hell
these animations
lol
let's tell them "I don't have internet"
laughter
they're like Hey, connect! Connect, you dummy!
eerrgghhh
Microsoft, why?
This is so annoying with only a keyboard.
Just a moment... they say...
Hello!
oh my gawd
[reading text on screen]
yeah, let me turn it off really quickly :D
Almost there.
ohnononononononooonooonooo
nonon
noo noo
nononononoo
it's really smooth tbh
let's see what monitor it's detecting
okay, it detected my monitor
Microsoft still supporting this monitor
As you can see, the taskbar isn't centered, because...
wtf Microsoft
Good old Device Manager!
And yup, Video Controller and Microsoft Basic Display Adapter (a.k.a. you need to install a graphics driver)
so, let's find the drivers for this computer's GPU and install them, I guess
Here we go!
If we open this...
And start...
I think it required I did this...
Compatibility > Windows Vista
HOW DID YOU KNOW!???
and OK
Yes
boop, install...
Next
Custom, I guess...
Yes
Detecting system...
Detecting graphics hardware...
Detecting Components
yup
Accept
Yup, install it.
The screen may flicker and/or go blank during installa...
Fameous last words.
coolooc
We have a display driver.
Oh, I was hoping the taskbar would be aligned to the center, but... NOPE!
And we now have a display driver.
Let's have a look at Device Manager...
Display adapters and... we... we do have it now.
yayay
It's working surprisingly flawlessly
And we have round corners, YO!
Oh yeah, we have Solitaire.
Okay, we don't.
Or do we?
Is it working normally?
Oh, it's working, what the heck?
It's actually working on this computer.
What the faaf?
I remember when Windows 10 first came out, this game wasn't working really well, but no... It's working.
The shadows may be a bit weird, but no problemo.
Skip this installation.
Installation complete, they say
As you can see, a perfectly functional Windows 11 installation.
Yup.
As you can see, this computer IS compatible with Windows 11, even tough Microsoft says it isn't.
YAY