Welcome to another Markus Computer Entertainment video!
Today we are taking a look at an operating system you might be familiar with - Windows 10.
You may be wondering - why are we taking a look at Windows 10?
The thing is, it's not an ordinary version of Windows 10.
It's a really special version of Windows 10
To start, let's turn on this computer and see what's going to happen...
So, first of all, we see the PH logo, which is cool, and the Windows loading screen.
Let's wait until this thing boots up and then start the overview.
This isn't a regular version of Windows 10, no no...
This is Windows 10 Amerliorated Edition.
Now you may ask: what's that?
It's a special version of Windows 10, where...
...basically most of the telemetry components have been removed and the whole system is made to be very lightweight.
The first thing they've removed is Windows Update.
You may ask: wouldn't that be really unsecure?
And the answer is "Yes, it is". But in order to midigate the risk, they made you a separate user account with standard privileges, so...
The default admin account has been removed and a new one has been created with its own password.
And you're going to need that password when installing programs and doing other stuff like that.
Let's start by logging in.
I haven't changed any passwords yet, which is... yay
"really secure"
But in a few moments we arrive at a DESKTOP, where...
Where you can see multiple things. First of all...
We have a different wallpaper.
very cool
Let's see if there are any other desktop background we can apply.
Okay, we have the default Windows 10 wallpapers...
All except the one we're missing
If we browse, let's see what happens.
This PC > Local Disk
Windows
Web
Wallpaper
sten
Windows... aha!
They have directly replaced the wallpaper file, which doesn't seem like the best thing ever...
And it seems they've activated the dark theme by default, I...
I'll be using Light theme for this video, because why not...
Lock screen, we can't modify, because some settings are managed by an organization.
Which is interesting, considering I am the only...
*clears throat*
...person that uses this computer.
So, I don't know who's my organization there.
We can still change the mouse cursor.
We have fonts and stuff...
It's basically just Windows 10, until you dig deeper.
One interesting thing is when we go and...
Open Network settings.
Then something interesting is going to happen.
It turns out that if we're connected through WiFi, it still thinks we're connected to the internet.
The plane!
Anyway, on the desktop, you can see on the right stuff I've installed myself.
And on the left you can see stuff that's interestingly pre-installed.
They've removed Edge from this, which is why they have Firefox installed as a replacement.
And I've got to say, Firefox isn't the worst web browser ever made, it's actually pretty good.
Let's see what websites we can visit once this thing decides to load...
Oh, okay.
It just showed the wait cursor for no reason.
That's the new tab interface by the way, it's just a white screen.
DuckDuckGo is the default search engine, so if you don't use it, you need to find a way to change it.
Google blocked my website again.
None of the search engines show my website on the first page, I don't know why.
What do you have against my website?
And in case you think it's not easy to find...
Then you can find it on my blog, my YT channel about page, my blogs, my GitHub, like it's on all of my profiles.
I don't get how search engines are unable to find it.
Just to show how easy it is to get to these websites using external links....
That's my blog, and right there is a link to my website.
I don't understand how search engines are unabl...
But the next program that's built-in is Mozilla Thunderbird.
So, if you're the type of person, who likes to use a desktop program to view your e-mail, then you can use this for that. It's like...
It's basically like a Mozilla's version of Outlook, in case you were wondering what it is.
Another interesting thing they've done is remove all .appx packages i.e. everything from the Microsoft Store including the latter itself.
If we open the start menu, the only things under the Apps, are...
...Settings and Snip & Sketch
It's the one you can use for making screenshots and stuff.
For a specific region on a screen.
Windows+Shift+S, does it work? Yes it does, so...
So, this feature still exists. We also have the Windows Terminal.
This is a new command line for Windows 10+ versions.
So, if we run "winver"...
It's Windows 10, build 21H1 or first half of 2021
Which means it isn't the newest version ever made.
Did they update it before, so that it would have...?
Yea
There are no temperatures shown here.
But at least you have the new Task Manager.
And if you open the file browser, you may notice it's quite fast on this computer.
The second thing you may notice is that we're missing a ribbon interface.
It's just a Windows 7-style menu, which is fine, but if you prefer the ribbon, it may be a disadvantage.
The reason I went on a tangent with the VLC media player is because it actually replaces the Windows Media Player.
If we can find a video to play...
YAY
It seems to have gotten stuck...
So you can play YouTube videos using VLC, that won't be a problem.
The next thing that's bundled here is ONLYOFFICE Editors, to stay in line with the minimalistic approach of this OS.
Then you can use OnlyOffice, which is a free version of Microsoft Office, which is fine.
Wow, it's taking a while to load an empty document.
Let's see if this thing that was in Word works here...
My overhead camera stopped recording :/
And it looks like it didn't work :(
Which is sad.
You can insert a bunch of stuff here.
You also have spreadsheets.
And once again, it's loading an empty spreadsheet, like...
Like what?
It's an empty spreadsheet, why does it take so [BLEEP] long time to load?
So, this is the presentation.
So, we can make a wonderful presentation
about why Windows 10 Ameliorated Edition is the best version ever.
And as you can see, our amazing presentation is finished.
And why is it the best version?
Because it just is the best version.
I don't even need to list any more reasons than that.
That was my presentation, thank you for watching, yay
Two [BLEEPING] slides
Another thing on the desktop that's built in is the RECYCLE BIN!!!
And if you open the recycle bin...
Here's some stuff I've added, such as FileZilla...
paint.NET, which is actually a decent picture editor
Let's see if my phone is... (it's not)
One of our cameras is offline.
probably
Capture device offline
Did the camera app just crash?
How is it possible that the camera app just gives up?
I'm going to pause the recording and free up some space...
he-he-hello
Welcome back!
Anyway, where were we left off? Right, paint.NET
Okay, this is Notepad++, a bit more powerful version of Notepad, that I installed.
XnView, which I hadn't even opened :D
I really don't like when programs automatically create desktop icons. Just look at this situation!
Settings are really minimal.
We have system settings.
If we go here, you may notice that Windows doesn't tell us if it's activated or not.
In this modified version of Windows, the activation feature has pretty much been completely removed, so...
No more comments about that.
Oh yeah, we can access files that are stored on a computer right next to us, yay.
Let's have a look at some pictures.
from "what the hell" folder
then, let's have a look at...
I can show you this one.
There are a bunch of pictures here that I don't want to show you.
Not that they're vulgar or anything, but...
I just don't want to show them to you.
We're not doing anything productive here, so I think it's safe to end the video here.
Thank you for watching this terrible video!
Press all the buttons...
Such as like or dislike...
comment
You can also hit the "Subscribe" button, why not, if you like this sort of crap.
Thank you for watching!