Welcome to yet another Markus Computer Entertainment Episode!
In this video, we're taking a look at an interesting operating system
called Chrome OS Flex.
Now, you may ask: what's Chrome OS?
Chrome OS is basically Google Chrome turned into an operating
system.
Let's choose "Estonia"
Keyboard, Estonian please...
OK
Start
oh...
Let's connect to WiFi
yay
Loading...
wow
Here are some licenses for MPEG-4 and AVC codecs...
Searching for updates...
[On-screen text] Who's going to use this Chrome device?
Yes, me
Log into a Chromebook device
okay
yes, enable sync
Google Pixel 2 - that's not my phone.
It's a Xiaomi.
Agree and continue
Here are all of my bookmarks and stuff.
Now, let's boot this computer.
First of all.
To see if anything interesting happens.
boom, we see the boot logo
And BOOM, in just a few seconds, we arrive at the login screen!
You may notice something - we have the option to install
Chrome OS Flex
Even tough we booted from internal storage.
Because, if you take a look, there are no USB devices inserted.
On neither side.
You can see there are no USB drives and nothing is sticking out
There are no thumbdrives inserted.
But you may ask - why do we have the option to install?
The reason is simple - I installed this OS incorrectly.
What I thought I had to do, was...
I downloaded the .BIN file, which contained this operating system.
I used the most complex method for getting this OS into the internal
drive.
First, I booted onto an Arch Linux Live CD.
Using optical media, with an external USB optical drive.
And I had the image of Chrome OS on a flash drive.
I booted onto the Live CD, I mounted the flash drive
onto a specific mount point.
I did all of this in command line.
I used the DD command to clone the image onto the internal storage
of this laptop.
And I thought that's the way I was supposed to do things.
You may ask - why didn't I just remove the internal storage from this
computer and put it into another computer
using a SATA cable or something.
The problem with that is this laptop has integrated storage.
The internal memory is soldered onto the motherboard, which means
it's not really that simple to just pull it out of the computer.
That's why I did it like that.
But now I found out, I could have just cloned the BIN file onto a
thumbdrive using the DD command
and then booted into that flash drive and from there installed it.
.  I did try to do that after recording, but  .
.  it didn't work, because the installer tried   .
to install into the /dev/sda block device, even
tough the internal storage is actually at
/dev/mmcblk0, and I couldn't find a way
to change the install location.
But who knows, maybe this was a better method, because maybe it
wouldn't have even worked.
It actually didn't (lol)
On the installer, I clicked Try Chrome OS Flex, or something like that.
And it works.
I logged in with my Google account.
And we're at the login screen.
If we take a look, we can see that Bluetooth has been turned on. We can
also adjust the brightness.
8 hours, 42 minutes till battery gets empty. I am not sure how accurate
this is, since I haven't used it a lot, other than the setup.
And we're connected to our WiFi network, which has a strong signal
strength.
The signal is strong, because we're on the 2.4GHz band.
Even tough there's also 5GHz WiFi, but that's because this laptop
doesn't support 5GHz. But that's okay.
But it seems I have to enter my Google password, so...
And even tough my account has 2FA, it doesn't require additional
authentication here.
That's somewhat interesting
So, now you can see this thing.
If I take a look at my phone, we see "Smart Lock - Device Chromebook
is unlocked"
So, if I lock the laptop now.
Then lock.
And if we turn on Bluetooth here.
BOOM, the screen has been unlocked.
I turned off Bluetooth and Chrome OS didn't like it.
That's our profile picture. That's actually my Google account image.
Let's put the phone closer, maybe then.. yup.
So, now it worked, as you saw.
If I put the phone closer (so it could hear)
It may actually be detecting the distance from the device.
We can capture the screen. That may actually be a good idea.
If I only had a flash drive... wait I might actually do.
Sort of unscripted, but I do have a flash drive nearby.
Let's plug the flash drive into the computer.
Removable device found
Unfortunately, at least one drive partition couldn't be mount... what?
So, you're saying that...
The fact that ChromeOS couldn't find the second partition
is quite weird, considering that if I connect this flash
drive into my Windows computer, it's detected as a
FAT32 file system, which should be compatible
with Chrome OS.
Open Media Vault
Oh wait, so I have Open Media Vault here.
Which is what I used for making my NAS server.
That means we can format it.
How do you format a drive partition in Chrome OS.
Format this device, there we go.
666MB worth of files will be erased
First of all, this flash drive is obviously bigger than 666MB.
Second, what the hell?
Why 666?
Theme Creator, My IP Address, yeah, I'll definitely show my IP address
to you.
We have a bunch of applications here, but I was wondering if it's possible
in settings to...
I was wondering if there's a terminal, where we could run mkfs, or something like that.?
mkfs.[filesystem] is a command, which lets you
format file systems in Linux and other Unix
like operating systems.
Oh, we do have a terminal, maybe we can use it.
Okay, set up.
Where can I turn Linux...
Where do I "turn on Linux"?
It's in quotes, because Chrome OS is actually Linux itself. By the way,
it's based on Gentoo Linux. I don't know what they're talking about.
Reset settings. POWERWASH
Can't we just search from settings?
Linux
Set up development environment, there we go.
Go! Go!! GO!!!
Are these some kind of placeholders, that actually don't work?
I just want to delete my drive partitions.
Let's hit the "+" button.
Oh, we can open multiple tabs, where we have this menu.
Can we enter TTY?
TTY is a text based command line interface in Linux systems. Generally, you can access it by pressing Ctrl+Alt+[F1-F12] key combinations.
Nope. No TTY for us.
So, I can't even erase partitions. Wow.
And if we go and format the device, it's only 666MB.
But it's fine, because I can correct the tilted screen in my editing
software, so it shouldn't be a problem.
Any way...
Messages
Okay, so I have to pair my Android device.
And do it using a QR code.
I'm going to blur or remove it from the screen using another method,
so that you couldn't scan it.
But I wonder, what would happen if you (the viewer) did scan it.
What else? Google Meet, which allows you to organize meetings.
Gmail.
We noticed a new login to your Google Account from a Chrome OS
device.
Social Media
Patkov Rekordér?????, thank you for subscribing!
Do we have spam e-mails?
Hurray, there's not junk mail!
I'm disappointed, I really wanted to show some spam to you.
Is YouTube something, that's just going to work?
I wonder, if that's also just a website.
Yes, it's just a web page.
If we go to my channel, we can watch some stuff.
I actually have multiple extensions specifically for YouTube, but they
aren't applied here.
As a comparison, if we open Chrome.
Which opens surprsingly quickly on this machine.
Oh my god.
I almost showed you my weather. Wait, where's the weather?
Oh, that's where it is.
That's what you're not supposed to see.
I forgot where I had the weather.
Actually, I'll change the layout a bit.
Now you can't see the weather.
Now you can see the news.
If we take a look at an article.
Then we can read it.
We need to turn on advertising cookies to read this article.
Altough, I did see a bit of this article, before the popup.
Just in case
yes
And we can see the current clock time around the globe.
If we open YouTube here, and stay in Chrome...
Then it starts thinking about it for a while, but...
The reason we're not seeing the changes is because we haven't
configured these extensions.
Okay, let's set it up in a way, which I had...
And now our thing has been applied and if we take a look at it.. yup
All of our extensions do get applied.
[plays video]
cool
Let's play a random video, which I've liked.
What the hell, let's just do screen recording.
Oh... We do actually have the video option.
The question is, where is it saving to?
Microphone...
The downloads folder
okay
save
3, 2, 1
Now, you should see the image more clearly, at least I hope.
Mr. Bean in Half-Life 2, that's a pretty funny video.
Now let's see what...
Okay, it's loading.
It's not the smoothest thing in the world.
YouTube was working, let's see if we can copy the address from
somewhere.
Copy URL
Let's just open in Chrome, let's see what happens.
I pressed F5 and this happened.
Fn+F5?
So, we opened some sort of a workplace switcher?
Let's call it, I don't know, "Files"...
Oh, it went back.
Everything stopped responding.
I modified the URL awkwardly.
We may have something that actually is going to work.
okay okay okay
fine fine fine
list=LL?
We can see the video, but we can't see the rest of the page
And the video froze
Come on, you can play videos
hello?
okay, everything loaded up
And we can watch a Mr Bean parody without issues.
Even tough, yeah there were a couple of problems.
For example, the fact that the page took 50 years to load.
So, web browsing is something that's totally possible
What's this? Enable highlight experiments?
Media tab section tab search
Scroll tabs
IC
So, if we have 50 tabs open, we can scroll through them.
Restart
So, if we restart Chrome, the whole interface reboots.
Interesting...
So, interesting fact, the whole system is built around Google Chrome
Let's see what happens if we open 50 tabs.
"Useful stuff", that one has a lot of pages.
Are you sure you want to open 48 tabs? Yes.
I'm already regretting my decision.
But everything's fine.
Everything isn't fine.
Interesting, do 48 tabs fit on the screen here?
Let me count them
46... (wind) all of them fit on a single bar
For some reason I counted 49, I might have opened 49, but I'm pretty
sure it said 48 tabs.
You're telling me that the only way to test this feature is to open
100 tabs?
Like, what?
Interestingly, we can actually browse Arch Wiki
I have to scroll down on the touch pad, to make it scroll down.
Let's see how much free space we have. Can we change the desktop?
If we go here and press "Files"
And if we're on another desktop, we have Google Chrome here.
Huh, it saved only a little bit. It didn't record for a long time.
*gasp* I know why it stopped recording. It's because we restarted
Google Chrome!
I'm pretty sure that's the reason, but...
I can't say for sure.
And Microphone enabled...
Record
Okay, so we're recording.
And if we refresh here...
How do you refresh in Chrome OS?
3.3GB is available, huh...
So, you're telling me we can only utilize 3GB out of the 16GB of
internal storage this laptop has.
Windows help and maintenance
Browse with Microsoft Edge in Windows
But I'm using Chrome OS
R.I.P. Microsoft
Okay, let's close this window
I bet 2GB of RAM will be freed from me doing just that.
Well, this laptop does have 2GB of RAM, but...
What was... office.com?
office online
Can you use it without an account?
So, you have to sign in...
And if we enter the code...
Microsoft... which one?
Okay, that one.
Enter
(that code expires every minute)
Yes, stay signed in.
Good evening!
Document, what is a document?
Okay, it's an empty document, which means we can insert whatever
we want here.
Simple websites work fine, but if we do something more complex...
Let's see if we can do this with the web version...
10 comma 10
YO, we can...
So, unlike in our Ameliorated Edition video, this actually worked.
We generated some dummy text.
[trying to read the first sentence of Lorem Ipsum, but it's backwards]
We generated 10 paragraphs of Lorem Ipsum.
We can change fonts and stuff. Office fonts.
So, here are all of the fonts that are normally included with Office...
Comic Sans MS
Best font ever.
It's quite slow. But that isn't Chrome OS' fault, that's the laptop's fault.
I'm also recording, which is also something you need to consider.
I'm choosing the ugliest fonts.
Paid fonts?
What?
So, you're saying that an ugly font called Papyrus is paid?
Second question, is Curlz MT paid?
Is there even Curlz MT?
That's Curlz MT
There's not.
Is Segoe UI Semilight paid? No, it's free.
So, a font that looks good is free, but a font that looks ugly is paid?
Let's find another font that might look good.
Is Trebuchet MS free?
Trebuchet MS
Yes, Trebuchet is free.
Calibri is obviously free, since we already used it.
Is Arial free?
Arial is free.
This video just turned into an Office Online roast.
We can add references.
We can add a footnote and a table of contents. That's it.
Meet the application launcher! Yes, I don't care!
Let's see if our own website works.
YAY
A new Markus Computer Entertainment episode about a modified
version of Windows 10!
Make sure you check it out. Yay!
If you haven't seen it, then you should check it out.
Check the card
Wallpapers, let's download a cool wallpaper.
Let's download our channel banner.
I need to tap with 2 fingers to open this popup menu.
If I right click on the touch pad, then it doesn't work for some reason.
Huh, we don't have an option to directly set it as the desktop
background.
Is it somewhere in this menu?
I found a feature that's in Firefox, but isn't in Chrome.
Setting as the desktop background.
Let's name it... yes... Save
The download has been finished.
Is there another shortcut key I can use. Can I do this?
No.
Because in Windows, if you press Ctrl+Win+Arrow key, then you can...
Set as desktop background, finally I found a thing!
Did it do it? Yes, we have a new desktop background!
This can be confusing. It's on another workspace, but it's marked
with a dot, which can easily be confusing.
Alt+Tab... Alt+Tab works.
72 words
Let's play a game called "Infinity"
Let's see if we're able to play it.
It's basically a game where you try to jump, but not fall.
Really primitive, but...
And if you're using Microsoft Edge, turn of "Efficiency Mode",
otherwise you're going to experience issues...
Let's just say that.
.    (the framerate drops significantly)    .
We have Game of Life, so...
We can do this thing and yay...
Wow, it just went through between these two
We also have extensions
Which we already had
So, we can edit some cookies, if it ever decides to load.
Edit This Cookie
We can see all the modifiable cookies
A simple extension that let's us change cookies.
So, if we set it to "en-US", after reloading, the page should be in English...
Yup.
If we set "theme" to "dark", then that should activate dark mode.
Yup. We can edit cookies very easily.
If we go to the homepage, we see the dark theme is also active here...
And if we open the channel database, then everything is correct
here.
We can even log in with our manager account.
And boom, we can add records to databases and stuff...
But there's another thing Chrome OS offers in addition to
simple Google Chrome.
Some additional things I wanted to show you.
All of your apps are here. What is discover?
Welcome to Chrome device
So, there are some tips and stuff.
Benefits. [Whisper] No offers are available!
What's new? Hourglass!
Record more with screen capture tool
That's a feature we just took advantage of.
Customize docked magnifier size
Personalize your desktop
Documents, which is probably just Google Docs.
Calculator
Okay, that's a number.
Okay, that's the accuracy.
My IP address, does it work?
Oh, it's actually loading the page.
It's an IPv6 address.
Google Chrome 103
Camera
Which actually works.
Chrome Caaaaanvas?
Is that some sort of painting application?
It's some sort of handwriting application.
Let's draw a weird face.
What am I even doing. Wait, that's turned into a balloon...
I accidentally drew a balloon
What are those eyes?
Try to draw something with a laptop touch pad.
I accidentally middle clicked, I don't know how that happened.
World's tallest person.
Who has the longest arms in the world
What is this?
So, we drew a really weird kite.
A very weird man
And a very weird balloon
Wait, there's something wrong with the image.
This wind man... what, wind man?
I accidentally said Wind Man, oh my god.
Wind Man
with a portable black hole and a
kite
That's my description for this image.
"Save as image", yes.
Let's call it "Wind Man.png"
a wonderful drawing
Gallery
so that we can check out our awful drawing
Crop
Let's crop it a bit
boom
boom, we edited a picture
wow
Save or Save As.. Save, just overwrite it.
Did I see something about editing videos or was I hallucinating?
Oh, watch videos in full screen or picture in picture.
oh, how boring
no editing
What's Text?
Oh, so you can type stuff.
Caution! This is medicine. Before consumption, carefully read info
page inside the package...
I wasn't typing my fastest here, but most if this has to do with the
fact that I was using a laptop keyboard here, while I normally
use a desktop keyboard.
Let's save it as something.
For example, "Medicine advertisement.txt"
boom
Medicine advertisement.txt
So, if we open files...
Oh, now it switches the workspace.
And we can see our stuff, including the screen recording we made
It didn't even record sound.
It isn't the worst screen recording in the world, but you can do
better, let's just say that.
And the file sizes are actually pretty small, so...
Google Maps, yeah
oops
I obviously don't want to show my location.
Because that would be...
Yeah, it's showing my current location.
Boom. Fork, it's showing my search history and I don't want you
to see that.
You see, that's where I live, Estonia
Let's drag the man into a random spot.
Where are you going to land?
God knows where we ended up landing.
OK
Pihkva province
Where else could we go?
Guys, I went to Tagavere
We can move around and stuff.
Look at bins and a pile of logs that by now has probably disappeared
I bet, because this is from July 2011.
That's when street view was last updated in Estonia.
But yeah, we explored Estonia a bit, pretty fun.
Play Movies, we can see some films.
Eciffo, if it decides to load in the next century.. oh
The webpage isn't available
Good evening!
This menu. Discover nearby, what does this do?
whawhawhawhawhawhat is that?
Google Pixel 2? It's not a Pixel 2, it's a Xiaomi.
But Google thinks that's what phone I have, probably because
I have custom firmware on my phone that's probably built on
top of Pixel 2's original firmware.
Personalization, what does that do?
Screensaver
It's a lot more boring than I expected.
Celsius, because I can't directly read Fahrenheit.
Is there a preview option? Obviously you don't need a preview
option lol
We can't even take a look at the screensvaers.
Change device account picture
So, we can apply a watermelon as our account picture.
An animated watermelon? No way!
Yaw on!
Oh, we can apply animated images.
What is this guy doing?
Your face when you just hit the dislike
What are these animations?
Oh, this guy is spraying some sort of a green dye.
Oh, cats
This bee won't stop flying around this guy.
Why are these clouds moving so quickly?
This person is just dripping the plant. Like, watering it drop by drop
till the next century.
Oh, dog
Are you writing down all of the videos I've disliked?
Oh, this guy is wearing that thing, which lets you turn your
phone into a VR headset.
This reptile guy is just reading.
First, why is it wearing glasses, second how can it read?
Bike ride is what this is called.
A person with what? With coffee? Oh, that explains some things.
Performer? What?
Performer?
I think what happened here is that in the original English version
said "Artist" and whoever made the translation used "Performer"
without context.
A person in snow. Why is there snow bursting out of this person?
It looks like there's snow bursting out, how it's looped.
Altough I understand, [weird sounds], that's how it's moving down.
I wonder what this guy is saying with a megaphone...
Yeah, it's a bird.
Just a still picture.
Is that a Tamagotchi?
Basketball
Vinyl record, I knew that.
Bike
Glasses, sunglasses
What's that supposd to be?
Pizza!? That's not a pizza!
Sandwich
So, they're just throwing the bread...
What could this be?
Without looking at the description, I have no idea...
Cappuccino, how?
I get that there are ice cubes. Ice water, okay.
Okay, that's ice cream.
Melting ice cream
But what's that thing down there? What is it?
If you're saying this is a puddle of melted ice cream, then why isn't
it changing size? Why does it keep the original size?
What is this?
Onigiri?
Oh, it's a kind of sushi?
Okay, I see what they're trying to mimic...
But I don't get how that, could be this.
Like, it's just a non-triangle with rounded edges and a rectangle
that's jumping up and down.
This one, we immediately understood, that it was a
watermelon.
What's this?
Avocado
How?
A botanist?
So, the rose she's pulling up, at the exact moment when the camera
pans, flourishes in one moment.
Okay, that's a hamburger, but why does it have legs, flying
sausages, and a hat?
Yeah, a graduate, but why is it a balloon?
Guitar
"Good bye" he says.
Waving. Waving? (it makes less sense in Estonian)
What are these translations?
Um, okay.
It's a planet, is it a...
what is this?
All of these animations are so creepy!
Speed camera
Robot?
Have you ever seen a humanoid robot that has a box for its head?
A shoe in disguise.
A boot.
Dancing van.
Oh, it's just a van, but I would totally allow it to be translated
to dancing van.
Where is it going anyway? It's driving in the middle of nowhere!
Oh, that's a watermelon.
Okay, they're calling that a melon and this a watermelon.
Almost all of these are creepy in my opinion.
I guess the ones that aren't animated not so much, plus this
melon here...
But, yeah... I'm not sure.
Still a bit creepy
If nobody ever told me this was cappuccino, then I would think this
was some sort of a loading animation for a web page.
Cheese seemed the least creepy out of all these.
Actually, I'm switching back to my Google account image.
Oh, we can manage other people.
Managing other people, that sounds kind of suspicous.
Night light, so if you want to do stuff in the dark, then you can do so.
Screen brightness, which is self-explanatory.
Bluetooth. Let's see if I can connect my headphones to this thing.
So, we're in pairing mode...
Connected
Okay, we're connected.
Presents...
So, we can... yeah we have Bluetooth.
We can use it.
Have we really seen everything except the guest account?
Screen recording has been saved, yay
Log out, shut down...
So, let's log out.
It took a bit to log out.
Add a person. Once again, a really weird use of language
And browse as a guest. Let's see what happens if we choose that
option.
So, it's just a standard Chrome guest mode.
And we only have a set of very basic things at our disposal.
Such as Gallery, Chrome, Files, Camera, and stuff.
Oh yeah, it's a Dev build of Chrome.
Oh, that's the wallpaper it's using.
Automatically hide the shelf. What's the shelf?
Okay, our downloads folder is private, but our USB is not.
Oh, we can search on Google.
Oh, another intersting thing. In guest mode, we have a different
keyboard layout.
One more thing. If we put the laptop into this position...
Then it goes into sleep mode
Hmmm
ok
Oddly enough, I didn't see the blinking power light.
Oh.
The laptop shut down instead of entering sleep mode. I wonder
why...
It just turned off.
What does "Add a person" do?
It opens a very bright setup wizard.
So, anybody can just add their profiles in Chrome OS, which is
interesting...
"Install Chrome OS Flex", which... ok
We have some screen recordings that I would like to transfer.
Let's see if I can do it.
So, we can just press Ctrl+C...
Open our thumb drive...
And press Ctrl+V
"Copying failed. An error has occoured"
Me anger
Very anger
I have an idea. What if we can copy it to Google Drive?
If we make a folder...
New folder
Let's rename it to "flex video"
And let's press Ctrl+V here.
And boom, we can just copy-paste from the file browser.
That's pretty fantastic.
Just like that, we're doing stuff.
You think you can copy 223MB in 4 seconds?
These files are copied, but it takes additional time to sync these
files.
And that 4 minutes, makes much more sense.
Phone Hub
Google Pixel 2? Once again, it thinks we have a Pixel 2.
We can see that my device has 17% remaining battery, which is
incorrect, because it actually has 16% remaining.
Is it still syncing, where can we see the notifications?
If something fails, I can do stuff off-screen.
4 hours till the battery is drained, now I believe this estimate a bit
more.
Shut down
The laptop has been shut down
So, Chrome OS, is it a good operating system?
It depends on how you use your computer.
If you mostly use your computer for web browsing and only
occasionally do something else, but not a whole lot.
If you exit the browser, the only thing you might do is browse
files...
Then Chrome OS will do the job for you.
Is Chrome OS for everybody? Obviously not.
But that's it for this Markus Computer Entertainment episode,
thank you for watching!