Galculator
What if I told you that...
200 euros!
So, this is the URL, where you can find this picture.
Markus computer entertainment
Licensed by:
Markus entertainment Estonia
Welcome to another Markus computer entertainment episode!
My name is Markus Maal, from the channel mmaal (markustegelane)
or... yes, mmaal (markustegelane).
Or was it maalm (tegelanemarkus)? No, it was mmaal (markustegelane)!
Anyway, today we are taking a look at an interesting operating
system called MX Linux.
Or is it 1010 Linux?
To be honest, I'm not sure how you're supposed to pronounce it...
But what I do know is that this is the most viewed Linux
distribution on distrowatch.com
In case you don't know what's distrowatch.com
then it's a website, where you can browse and view different distributions.
Compare them
This website also collects statistics
About how many people watch specific pages.
And the computer where we're going to install MX Linux to is
the legendary blue HP laptop, i.e. HP Stream.
And we're installing it from a USB thumbdrive.
Which this time is a Kingston drive.
So, HP Stream, bow to the viewers.
What an amazing bow from the HP Stream laptop!
But now, let's boot this laptop.
F9 opens the boot menu, so let's tap that key.
And we're on the boot menu.
And let's choose Kingston DataTraveller, okay..
It thought about it for a while. Needed some time to think
about it.
So, this is the boot menu for our flash drive.
As you can see, we have multiple options here.
That's because we're able to boot multiple operating systems
from this flash drive.
This is where all of our boot options are.
We're going to choose MX Linux here.
In case you are wondering, this uses Ventoy for the boot menu.
(spells out the name)
It's a wonderful tool that allows you...
...to boot multiple operating systems from a single flash drive.
And to add an operating system, you just drag and drop an
ISO file, it's a fantastic thing.
But let's boot MX Linux
It uses GRUB, as you might be able to tell.
First of all, we see a cool menu.
The first thing it selected here is Language - Keyboard - Timezome
This is where we select the language.
As you can see, we selected the language, keyboard layout,
timezone. They're all correct now.
We can return to the previous menu.
Okay
What's under >>> Advanced options <<<
We can... (lists options)
Memory test, hmmmm....
Memory test in UEFI mode.
I know that MemTest86+ is something that used to exist.
But what kind of a memory test this is?
I wonder
Retrieving hardware info, please wait...
And from here, we can boot.
Let's boot MX Linux
So, we can see some kind of a wallpaper.
We can also see the mouse cursor.
We can see some kind of a taskbar on the left side of the screen.
I was just typing in my WiFi password, but...
What's the ____ing keyboard layout it set for us?
That's obviously not my password.
So, I'm going to, yeah...
Okay, that was our problem.
It selected "et" as the keyboard layout.
But "et" is Amharic???
Now let's see if it's able to make a connection.
Connection established - wow it worked.
Let's select "Install MX Linux"
The code name is "Wildflower".
Which is about as weird as "Singing sunflower", if you remember
my Enso OS video.
(reads text on screen)
So, we can change the keyboard settings
Can we add the correct keyboard layout?
So, on the left we have instructions on how to install this OS.
(reads stuff again)
Okay
IC
So, we can set how much the /home...
Okay, I was trying to my flash drive...
We're not going to use a /home partition, because it's just a
test system.
But if you were using it on a real system, where you have your
personal files and configuration files, then it's a recommended
option.
Drive encryption, in case you want to do that, but since this
is a test system, nobody cares.
Are we sure everything is 100% correct? Yes.
ESP is an EFI System Partition, okay.
That's okay
Next
Okay, Estonia
Oh, so if you have Windows, you can use local time.
Service settings
You can specify which services your system uses.
Nice, so you can make a super minimalistic system.
If you really want to.
Login name, uhh...
Autologin, because it's just...
Okay, that's also pretty interesting.
So, if you make modifications in this live environment, you can
keep those changes.
uhm
Okay, now we just wait...
Okay, so we can press → Finish
Reboot
Okay, we can see the boot menu.
Yes, this is from the internal storage now.
Advanced options, so we can select our kernel if we want.
Memory test, once again, a really useful tool.
System setup, which I assume is the BIOS...
Let's verify that's the case.
For this laptop, it should open the "Startup menu"
Yup.
So, we can do stuff in the startup menu.
We can press "Continue startup" and just boot it.
We can see that Linux gets loaded and...
And we see a black scree... wha?
We can see a different boot screen.
Here's the flash drive, we don't need it anymore.
And we can see the default desktop background.
MX-21.1 "Wildflower"
Okay. We can plug in the flash drive if we want.
I was trying to plug in the USB backwards, yay
proof that nobody can plug in the USB
.           on the first try           .
The first thing I want to do is find some sort of a program...
Okay, here's my flash drive.
I don't like these defaults.
Single click to select items.
If I hover over an icon, it gets selected. If I click on it, I enter.
And the connection has been established.
yay
First of all
xfce terminal
It's using the XFCE desktop environment.
Let's enter...
sudo apt update
It's based on Debian.
sudo apt install obs-
studio
okay, our keyboard layout is incorrect
for some reason
we have to set it up again
actually, we don't have to wait this long, because
OBS Studio is already in the menu
let's see it if starts up
Okay...
So, I got some sort of a screen capture working.
With my capture device.
* wind *
If we take a look at what's in here...
We have a text editor here.
Where we can type, you know what.
Yea, our keyboard layout is still wrong.
How do we change it?
What does this button do? It's a minimize button,
are you kidding me?
It looks like a download button.
Oh.
Oh, it's a checkbox.
Maybe let's change it to "no dead keys".
YAY, it works!
This text editor is mostly meant for development and
programming.
In some ways it's like Notepad++
That's why it was under "Development". Icon Browser
So, we can look at our icons.
We have "Document scanner", which we can test if
we connect a scanner to our laptop.
Actually, we can do that.
Okay, document scanner, let's see if it works.
Does it find our scanner? Yup.
p
What happens if we scan? Unable to connect...
Markus Maal - Not connected
So, they still haven't fixed the issue in Linux, where...
...my scanner won't work unless I manually copy the
firmware file, which is a bit annoying.
LazPaint, what's this?
Oh, we can draw!
What is this program? I've never seen it.
It's like paint.NET, but not really.
What happens if we... OMG we can render water!
But are there any options for modifying this water?
What's plastic?
We can, noise filter.
Okay, here we can modify stuff...
But for those other options, nope.
Twirl
Ah, I see...
An amazing work of art, as you can see.
Import 3D object... wow
There aren't a lot of languages here.
It actually seems like a useful program.
And we can choose colors
Let's save our masterpiece!
"noname", yes that's a very good name.
Okay, let's use that format.
Yeah, a pretty good program actually.
Uhm.
LibreOffice Draw
Which is a standard piece of software in the
LibreOffice suite.
Where you can make drawings.
In addition to plans and stuff.
Okay, that's good enough.
Close enough to the M.C.E. logo.
Let's save as.
Let's call it...
Uhm
Oh, what's this?
164 updates
Okay, it's just...
...output for the apt command.
And it's showing all the packages that can be updated.
Full upgrade, okay.
Password: 123abc
The most secure password ever.
* contenplating life choices for a second *
And now we can install all the updates.
* wind *
What?
Firefox Web Browser - since we have an internet
connection, we can use i
Fire starts here
The MX Blog
In case you are wondering what they're up to, you
can just follow their blog.
And we can read about the version we're using right now.
They have different versions. They have the xfce
version, which we're currently running
They have a KDE Plasma version
They also have a fluxbox version, which is the most
minimal.
Plasma is a fancier DE that some people might like
more.
And Xfce is their main version
It's also based on antiX, which is...
antiX is based on Debian and MX Linux is based
on antiX Linux
* reading *
So, all of this also applies for MX Linux.
Just to prove to you that there is no systemd, let's try,
I don't know, end a service.
cool
So, if you try to run systemd commands, you can't.
Yes, we are using Linux without systemd.
Which is interesting to think about.
Here you can read about antiX, if you really want to.
But let's do a bit of self-promotion and watch our
own YouTube video.
Our sound output isn't on the capture device.
So, that was a short showcase of Firefox.
We're going through things quickly, because there
are a lot of things to take a look at.
Adblock
huh
oh
nice
okay, so...
hah, someonewhocares.org
What is this website?
dan pollock's homepage
hosts
Integrated Circuit
So, let's select it.
Success - your changes have been, yay
PPP
Which is a dial-up tool...
okay
Thunderbird
Will we log in with our...? No, we won't.
Transmission, which is...
...a torrent client. So, if you want to...
So, if you want to download/upload big files, then...
We have office software.
Including Orange... Orage calendar?
Orage global time
PDF Arranger
qpdfview
Globaltime
Local time, we can...
Probably add something
Okay, we want to see what time it is at...
At the South Pole in Antarctica.
That's a save button?
What? But why?
This is a window compacter button, so...
...you may have a lot of windows on the screen, but
you can make them really compact.
Oh yeah, Foliate, for reading e-books.
We also have Xfburn, which is used for burning
optical media.
AlsaMixer, huh
So, you can adjust the volume here.
So, you can adjust the volume using this cool
CLI tool.
Asunder CD Ripper
Which lets you read tracks from an Audio CD.
Clementine, which is for playing audio files and
listening to internet radio.
A simple MTP client, which is..
...for MP3 players.
There are some specific audio options and stuff.
OBS Studio, which I installed, but couldn't quite get
to work (on the laptop).
PulseAudio Volume Control
Which we tried to use, but is now a graphical
interface.
Yeah, you can hear audio now.
Because I am using an AUX cable.
AUX is a pretty good cable.
Web Cam Oid
Which is probably a webcam.
Okay, we can see a light...
...next to the camera.
Which means it's recording.
Okay, let's end this.
An ugly face.
I don't want you to see it.
Yo, we have games!
Let's play... LBreakOut...
What game is this?
Local game
Quick help
I did plan to play some games, but I didn't realize
there were some games included here.
Okay, so you are trying to...
ow
Everything is messed up.
Late at Night
owowowowowowowowowow
f
urgh
oh, multiball
200 euros!
Let's go! 200 euros!
* laughter *
ha
No.
Game Ogre
Mahjongg
What kind of Mahjongg is this?
Okay, it's this kind of Mahjongg...
You just find pairs and click them.
But the catch is...
...you can't click here for example
You can't match these two, you have to pick ones that
are most outward and/or upward.
Peg E (not PEGI)
Jump pegs to eliminate them.
Okay, we can... huh
Is this like that game, which was like Checkers, but
not really?
Chinese Checkers, I guess...
Swell Foop
Is this what I think it is?
No, it's completely different.
Hey, I played a similar game in my Nokia episode!
A clip from the Nokia C2-01 episode:
About MX Linux, so we can see some information
about our operating system.
MX VERSION 21.1
We can see our CPU information.
You can see that we have a N3050 Intel Celeron.
Assorted useful tweaks (the bar is blurred to avoid
trademark infringements)
We can move the panel to the bottom.
Or we can move it to the right.
Uhm
If you are wondering why anybody would want to do this...
Then I can give an example usecase.
Let's say you have three monitors and on each display
you have the panel set up on a different edge for each
screen.
Let's say on the middle screen, the taskbar is on the
bottom...
On the left one, it's located on the left side.
And where should the taskbar go on the right display?
Well, of course to the right edge.
With a vertical alignment, so...
Window manager
So, we can change the window manager theme.
Maybe. Oh.
Okay, it only applies the theme after closing the...
Oh.
Let's open another window for previewing the changes.
Okay, thick border.
dark
comfort
Moheli
Arc (not the graphics card), which is...
Which is a pretty well know Linux theme, where the
icons actually make more sense.
Arc Dark
Arc Darker
Blackbird, which goes better with the rest of the window, but...
I don't like it.
Matcha (that is totally not how you pronounce it)
Actually, that's pretty much perfect.
Okay.
We can move the title to the left for example.
Appearance
So, you can change the theme for the window contents.
A darker theme, which fits much better.
We can change the icons.
So, let's use the correct icons...
We have fonts.
We can change it.
Let's set it to Adlam Regular.
* nice melody *
okay
I wouldn't use that font.
What's this font called?
Oh yeah, let's set it as the system fonts, then nobody
would get confused at all.
Let's use a lighter font.
Okay, it looks fine in my opinion.
You probably won't think so, but I don't care about
your opinion, because it's my computer.
* beautiful sound *
It doesn't look very good...
huh
Xfce, why aren't your panel settings opening?
Okay, let's put...
Let's switch back to mx-comfort
Oh, theme...
Okay, application, icon... okay.
Let's select that...
...themepack
Yup.
And now everything looks fine.
So, it turns out they do know what they're doing.
So, our internal display is called eDP-1.
I know DP stands for DisplayPort, but what is e?
What does "e" stand for?
Wait, what was quick system info?
code
uh, okay
oh, hello
drakcaP-ttelweH Primary
Type: Li-ion. Guys, we have Lithium Ions.
Health: 100%
Charged 35.9%
okay
Oh, so we can toggle Conky on and off.
If we want to.
We have a clock, date...
Hard drve, memory, and CPU usage.
Settings
Snapshot
Oh.
Uh... OH
ohhhh
So, if you want to make a bootable live environment
of your current configuration, then you can do that.
out.ogv
The reason I didn't use RecordMyDesktop here, was...
Let's just say this was the reason...
l... okay
Yes, that.
We have a task manager. Is it...? Okay, it's a
Gnome thing.
I have 100% seen this before.
yes, you did in the EnsoOS video
I wanted to try something. If I typed fortune, I didn't
work for some reason.
Yeah, it says "No fortunes found", I don't know why.
Let's make Tux say something.
moo
So, the penguin said...
MOOOOOOO!
A very useful program, as you saw.
What if I told you...
...that MarkuStation...
...doesn't exist!
It's actually a pretty cool effect.
To show that "hey, I hacked the Matrix", but no
it's just an animation.
Midnight Commander
okay, we have a lot of command line utilities
Accessories. That's where our CMatrix is.
Conky Manager
Which we can use for managing desktop widgets.
Oh, okay.
Okay, okay...
I'm going to change this background.
Let's use a more neutral background.
From a different directory!
backgrounds
Bee
wow
So, you have a lot of personalization options.
Actually, these are pretty nice wallpapers, I like them.
Oh, what's this?
Some kind of an abstract thing? Okay...
To be honest, I can't decide which wallpaper I want
to use.
Maybe the Conky Widget works with this background?
Oh, some kind of pipes?
yay
Actually, I'm going to choose this one, because
it does work with this widget.
Okay, we can choose what icons to show on the desktop.
Removable Devices
We personalized MX Linux a bit.
Galculator
What's a Galculator?
It's the Gnome Calculator, but they replaced
C with a G.
At least it's not as bad as KDE, where they but K in
front of everything.
the situation isn't that bad, but
you should get my point
Okay, let's calculate something.
Let's try... 2, square root...
times
the square root of 2
equals... oh
It's actually accurate.
nice
Okay, let's try one more thing.
Parenthesis, wait...
all clear
what
two?
uh... what?
1 divided by 7
uh... times...
seven
equals 1, correct!
We have scientific mode. What's paper mode? okay..
if we do bumbumbum plus bumbumbum, we get...
Scientific mode, which is...
There are a few programmer options here as well,
so we can...
sixty-nine factorial...
...is a big number
but if we do 70!....
Then it's also a really big number, waitwaitwait...
How big factorials can this thing handle?
100!
200!
10 000!
Okay, it can't handle that.
1000!
Okay, so it can handle 1000...
It's somewhere in-between 1000 and 10 000...
1753! is a number...
Now the question is, is the limit 1753 or 1754?
On of these two.
Leave your hypothesis in the comments!
1754!
Is a number! So...
So, the upper limit is 1754!
I wonder why this number specifically...
55 cosine
so, we keep clicking it until it doesn't give a different
answer from the input
okay
So, this is the trigonometric accuracy.
Pretty good calculator actually.
Featherpad, which is an alternate text editor.
Let's write, save, open, and delete a text document!
Press like or dislike
Comment
If you like these videos, press the "Subscribe" button
Self-promotion again, sorry about that.
Enter
And if we open the file here...
Then we can access it.
And we can delete it.
Nice
And so, we've done a small overview of this OS.
Screen capture.
So, we can screenshot the whole screen...
And...
and share it with everyone.
Host on Imgur™
Will it work?
Okay, so this is the URL where you can find this
image...
If you want to add this image to your own website...
...in HTML, Markdown.. BBCODE, which is also
apparently a thing that exists.
Just picture
okay
So, you can choose whether you just want the picture
or also a link to the picture.
We can also change the size...
Okay, this is the URL, where you can delete this image,
but I won't show it to you, because...
...otherwise you might actually delete it.
I forgot to copy the URL, which means I have to
look at it in the video, just like everyone else watching this video.
How sad.
One more thing, before we end this video, that
I would do, is to shut down the computer. WOW
Amazing
So...
Save session for future, why not, and shut down.
I don't know why that option still exists, but...
okay
So, the system has been turned off, and we
are seeing a black screen. Yay
We're going to stop the recording now.
LET'S STOP IT!
IT'S TIME TO STOP!
Credits
Edited by
Background music
Production software
MX Linux - Operating system
Ventoy - Flash drive multiboot solution
Audacity - Background noise recording and removal
OBS Studio - For saving video feed from the capture device
DaVinci Resolve 18 - Editing and 2D/3D graphics
Aegisub - For making the awesome subtitles
YTSubConverter - For converting subtitles
Firefox - A web browser (for uploading the final video)
Hardware featured
HP Stream Notebook 11 (laptop)
Samsung Galaxy Tab S7 FE (tablet, camera)
Elgato Game Capture HD60S (capture device)
Kingston DataTraveller 64GB (USB 3.2 Gen 1 flash drive)
Mustek BearPaw 1200CU Plus (scanner, for testing)
Thank you for watching!
YouTube channel: mmaal (markustegelane) [youtube.com/c/MarkusTegelane)
Odysee channel: MarkusTegelane (@MarkusTegelane:8)
©2022 Markus' videos