Today we are going to talk about a browser extension
which helps undo a stupid mistake from Google.
That mistake being the removal of dislike counts from videos.
We don't see a dislike count
The like/dislike ratio bar is also gone.
This is not my own choice, it's like this on every video.
And you maybe able to tell I'm not happy about this change, since I made this video.
This is my most popular video.
I chose this video to demonstrate how accurate Return YouTube Dislike might actually be.
Browser extension Return YouTube Dislike
This is a browser extension
tries to find the number of dislikes through certain methods.
The most depressing thing about this dislike situation is
that YouTube has even closed access to the APIs, which would have allowed you to see the number of dislikes.
I don't know why they did this.
I wouldn't even be that mad if they wouldn't have closed access to the APIs. Well, actually I may have been a little bit, but
I would have found ways to see the exact dislike count.
Unfortunately, this is no longer possible.
Right now they are extrapolating user behavior to find the dislike count.
People anyone who dislikes a video gets logged on their servers.
Yeah, here they explain how this works.
Let's have a look at the example video again.
If I have the extension installed, it would seem like the video has 133 likes and 2 dislikes.
I don't know why I have liked my own video, but...
(no comment)
Now, if I take a look at my most popular videos on my side....
We can see that it indeed has 133 likes
But it actually has 3 dislikes.
So, 1 more than this extension actually shows.
This also tells us that the extension isn't very accurate, in a sense that...
Well, it's about as accurate as it can be, okay...
Considering I can't give them my actual dislike counts, it's quite accurate.
But how do you install this extension? Well...
If you go to returnyoutubedislike.com/install
Then you can select your browser and...
...basically click it and..
For Chrome, it opens the Chrome Web Store and here you can...
You can just click "Add to Chrome" and for Firefox...
you can do the same.
For all of these browsers (except Firefox) you can use the Chrome Web Store.
It's a really useful add-on, you should definitely install it.
It helps me as well as you.
In a sense that if I see that a video has a lot of dislikes, I am able to tell there's something wrong with it...
in addition to comments, which point me to what is wrong.
If you see this comment on your video from me, then that means I liked that video...
Who disliked this?
well, maybe I liked it
But I just want to know who did it, like who disliked...
Thank you for watching!
Press like or dislike.
Install Return YouTube Dislike add-on, so that you can hit the dislike again.
And see dislike.
Okay, stop. I have to edit this crap, that's just...