Hello, hello!
Today we are going to play Minecraft
You may ask: haven't you played Minecraft already, Markus?
And the answer to your question is yes, I have played Minecraft on this channel before.
But I haven't played this version of Minecraft, at least not publically.
This is Minecraft Bedrock Edition.
yay
* Types YouTube world *
* wind *
Create
wow
wow, really?
the next part of the video uses a
TV effect, because why not
incredible
woah
where am i?
Why do I not see anything?
Oh, I had to press F1
Okay, I spawned into a snow world...
yes
That would be really great tough...
Oh, we have a rabbit.
Two rabbits
Let's chop this tree for a bit
Does this place have... oh nice!
Just like in the first Minecraft video, we're in a taiga.
But this time it's a snowy taiga.
snow
nice
Okay, now we have some materials to make stuff from.
I don't see sheep here, because snow.
laughs
There's a cavern here.
We're not going to go there yet.
hmmm
Let's make a crafting table
This game isn't in Estonian, because
okay
let's make something
Let's make a pickaxe.
and an...
axe
and... hmmm
let's chop some trees
huh, why did my framerate suddenly...
it's fine
just fine
okay, that's the akward moment where I'm going to have to take a break for a moment
to do something else
my hunger is going down
oh yeah, this is the version of Minecraft, that you can't pause
Because...
Because you can't
I don't know why, but you can't pause it.
Let's make a door
yay
the coolest door in this game
epic
um
We're going to make a really simple shelter, just so that Zombies won't eat us.
As you can see, it's high enough so that I can jump.
If this was 2 blocks, I wouldn't have been able to jump
Okay, so we're here.
I also need to build a floor, that would make sense.
Take a piece of wood...
oh, C418 music, nice
I should have made a shovel, but...
whatever
And now, let's build the ceiling.
okay
fun
oh
I had a...
And now we actually have a shelter.
We really should make a spoon right now.
Let's make a spoon.
Yeah, let's make a spoon.
For those saying that I can't dig straight down, yes I can.
okay
I'm digging a lot of stone, because I want to make more tools.
Because this pickaxe is going to break very soon.
or...
I should do some mining as well.
We have 27 stone.
Is that enough? I don't know.
We haven't found any coal yet.
I don't know, let's just make charcoal.
Because the time is ticking.
Can I just? There we go, we can just make more snow!
Then we can boop, boop, boop.
As you can see, nothing has happened here.
Let's make a furnace.
There we go, we have a furnace.
Let's chop some more pieces of wood.
If I remember correctly, in order to make charcoal...
We have to burn something, like, I don't know...
Our pickaxe
Do it to these logs, and then we get...
Charcoal
There we go, we have charcoal.
And then we can make some sticks.
And...
And some... okay
Okay, we did this at the very last moment.
We're good
We just have to survive the night.
Which shouldn't be that big of an issue.
I think that's enough for now.
Let's make a few more logs.
And let's make a pickaxe, that we just burned.
And some other things.
For example a sword
And an axe
I still haven't burned my spoon yet, but that's okay.
I'll now just have to wait, until it's day time, I guess.
For some reason, the frame rate is still trash.
Okay, we're hearing zombies.
Let's add a bit more brightness
FOV is fine.
Oh.
That explains a lot.
okay
That does explain a lot.
Yup.
The render distance was maxed out, that's why it was lagging so much.
So, that's why the frame rate... and now it's 60 fps no problem.
nice
We can't make a chest, because we don't have enough materials.
But what can we do? Well, we can make wooden buttons.
To open our door.
Could we...?
Oh, we haven't made any food yet, that's a problem.
But we can handle it.
I wouldn't go outside and fight the monsters right now. That would be a bad idea.
So, I'm just standing here waiting, until the sunrise.
That takes about 10 minutes.
If I'm not mistaken.
I don't know how much this... I think that still takes a bit hunger.
Oh, hello!
Hello, Sun!
Hello, Zombies!
I'm going to do something stupid. I'm going to eat rotten flesh.
* chomp, chomp *
But the trick is to stand still.
And so...
It shows me that there's a hunger effect, but...
But for how long? The world may never know.
I need to kill another spider.
Can we find more spiders?
omg, that biome
what
you?
oh my god, I'm...
omg, that's the most absurd...
oh my god, it's powder snow
dear god
You're going to need..
No!
Nonono!
Nonono!!
Nohoo!!!
Oh my god, an absurd way to die.
* laughter *
I'm wasting my stone right now.
Where... where's the spider?
I'm hearing a spider, but I can't see them.
Where's the spider?
I can't see it.
Okay, powder snow is dangerous!
* laughter *
um
okay
oh hello, we have a rabbit hide.
Let's go! The rabbit was crushed.
What else do we have here?
Okay, the trick is really simple, we have to...
We can do this.
no
How did you make...
...snow layers, I don't remember?
A weird crafting recipie
Okay, nope. Nonono!
I wasn't even inside it.
We really need some leather, basically.
I'm not even inside, what the heck, Minecraft?
I'm not even inside the powder snow, what the hell?
It's a lucky spawn in a sense that...
yes
Where did our arctic fox go by the way?
oh no
ffs
It's really annoying.
omg
I don't want to freeze!
This is so stupid.
Should we make a ladder? That seems like a good idea.
Let's make a ladder.
oh
the fox... the fox ate something right now
Is that?
Did I see something?
No, I was hallucinating
I can't jump!
I'm
I'm inside powder snow.
E
um
It's a really annoying situation.
There we go.
No we have some materials to make a ladder.
And some other stuff.
Let's make a beautiful coffin.
And then let's make...
a lot of sticks
there we go
we have 21 ladders
Now we can safely dig.
Let's see
uh oh
okay
Yeah, there's a reason they say not to dig straight...
dig straight down
hmmm
We're near a cave. I can hear zombies.
We're definitely near a cave.
Or near a spawner.
Or near a mineshaft, I honestly don't know.
I wouldn't go into a mineshaft right now with the resources i have
Though you could find some really cool stuff from there.
oh, it is a cave
how do I see my coordinates?
I don't know
We're going to put down some torches to avoid surprises...
oh hello, we found some coal!
fun
We can do stuff really well.
not ready yet
I made a chest and I am not even using it. Come on!
heh, okay
Let's get back up.
With our wonderful ladder.
Let's put that here for example.
And mayble let's do.
one
Let's put some stuff here.
stuff we don't need right away
what next
I wanted to make a trapdoor.
So that monsters wouldn't get down there.
Okay. Let's hurry!
there we go
that was just a fox
The fox is eating stuff.
what an animal
we have to wait 10 minutes again
But there's another problem - we don't have food.
Is that a cape?
Oh I actually have a cape!
I have a different cape here compared to Java.
I should have shown my face right? That is me.
A pretty ugly skin, isn't it?
Oh yeah, I wanted to do some stuff with a hoe. I don't know if it's...
If it's possible to grow anything in this biome.
But once again, we need iron, which is something we don't have.
W eare going to have to make a new pickaxe soon.
Let's do it again.
Imagine if I found diamonds and I couldn't even mine them. Come on...
That would be a horrifiying experience.
Maybe we're going to need it. Let's put half here.
Wait, I could have just. Wait...
Wow, I'm an idiot.
Let's make a basement.
Interesting idea.
is...
It's dark outsie
Urghh. I need to eat an my life is a bit...
shhh
First priority is going to be to find food.
um
yay
we need to use our first shot to go outside
This wasn't a good seed at all, so...
So, just like Windows RT, this world isn't that good.
The difference is that Windows RT is an operating system, not a Minecraft world.
CREEPER
oh no
we have a CREEPER problem
____
I didn't think about CREEPERs.
Oh no
CREEPERS
ffs
I CAN HEAR CREEPERS
THAT'S A PROBLEM
THAT'S A BIG PROBLEM
I don't have a _______ shield...
I don't have a bed.
I'm at a lonely _______ house...
And there are CREEPERs going around my house!
* laugh *
eurghh
oh
Where are the CREEPERs?
Hello, Zombie!
baegeugehehohi
your face was SUSpicous
Zombie Villagers, damn it.
eurgh
No! No! No!
We're dead! (3x)
We're dead!
We're not.
okay
we're not dead
Okay, we don't want skeletons.
We really don't want skeletons.
Okay, that's a big problem.
We need to escape this biome somehow.
Oh, rabbit!
Let's kill her!
Kill rabbit! With an... axe
Did we get food? No, we just got XP.
another rabbit
____
rabbit
There we go, we have food!
YO! We can eat!
Finally!
sheep
Come here!
_____
Help! We're drowning!
NOOOOOOO!
okay
where's the sheep?
PIG KILL PIG!
oink
nice
where's the sheep?
sheep, where are you?
SHEEP
ARE YOU SHEEP?
I want to kill you. Where are you, sheep?
Oh, hello fox!
sheep
Where are you, sheep?
I'M STARVING!
I want your wool and meat!
Where are you?
Come here!
Did this wolf just...?
Did the wolf just commit suicide?
just jumped down a cliff
yes, they actually did it
OK
Hello, sheep, I'm going to murder you!
And we got 1 wool.
We need more sheep. At least 2 more.
Is that a sheep? Sheep, come here!
I'm going to kill you!
Oh, that's not a sheep, it's just a fox.
Fox is a useless animal.
Okay, we have a chance of survival.
A realistic chance.
Don't ask me why I'm using stone and not other kind of blocks.
This surface is ugly.
just is
oh ____
It's hard to distinguish which one is powder snow...
I don't want to freeze!
okay
hmmm
If you are wondering why, then it's because we can get more blocks this way.
So that I can go further.
But if we reach home again, then...
We're going to be hungry again.
Plus, we get a good overview from here. Okay.
This place seems familiar.
But I don't see my house.
Oh, I didn't crack me bones!
Surprise, surprise
Okay, nevermind.
Where am I?
Where's my house?
Come on! Where's my house!
NOOOOO!
I need food.
Like, right now
* sheep chatter *
This is our house
Okay, here's our house, let's go!
Let's go! Why did I place this piece of wood?
The world may never know.
We can eat! Why was our door open? Okay, that's suspicous.
Herobrine has visited our house.
Yeah, right.
Maybe I just forgot to close the door.
That's also realistically possible.
We got a bit.. a bit...
A bit of mutton.
Then we have some rabbit meat and stuff.
* chompy chomp chomp *
And now we're healing.
VERY SLOWLY
Man, we really need to get some food.
We need a lot of food.
Let's see if we can...
Can we find a water source?
If we only had scissors, so that we could cut tree leaves.
Okay, the fire extinguished.
We're almost healed.
Oh, we didn't get the hunger effect.
Funny
If we took the next one, we totally would tough
Okay, we definitely want...
Let's use the other pickaxe, so that we can mend both later.
Oh, it says 63, so we're not that deep.
Oh, lapis!
Oh, we can mine it!
nice
We get a lot of XP. But is there anything else here?
We have lapis lazuli, so that we can do blue stuff.
dig, dig dig...
This right here is...
What was it? Copper, right? But copper isn't that useful to us right now.
Unless we use it as a weird building material.
And we can mine it with a stone pick.
Maybe we can make a lightning rod as well...
Why didn't you increase your ceiling height?
okay
I'd rather not...
Okay, the trapdoor was just close. I was like what the hell...
We can't even make a bed.
Oh, we can make blue wool. We can make a blue bed, if we...
If we get enough wool.
I think we're going to make a blue dye.
let's put it here
we can make a blue bed if we get enough materials
I don't know how long I'm going to play this.
Probably 2 hours to make an okay YouTube video.
My health is full and my hunger is at a level where I don't need to eat.
Rotten flesh is like an emergency food.
Can I do this? Yes, I can. Nice.
Let's say if a  CREEPER blows up our house...
Then I will not immediately die.
But I still need to plan what to do.
I should use these stone blocks as a temporary replacement and stuff.
Hopefully it's not going to blow up my chest, otherwise that would be a problem.
Oh, I'm hearing spiders! We can use spiders to make a bow and arrows, but..
for arrows we're going to also need chicken, so that's an issue.
Actually, I can also mine at night.
Okay, there we go.
There we go. We can mine right now, right?
Yeah, iron can spawn anywhere.
But they are rarer compared to...
There we go, we found iron!
We found iron!
Hallelujah!
Hell yes
we can do stuff now
We're still going to have to cook it tough.
Let's see if we get flint. Yes
We got flint.
I don't know if 8 iron is good enough for now.
Okay, we just
Just saw a mirror image in OBS and it made me...
oh my god
go away, you silverfish
_______ idiots
Why did you de-spawn?
what the hell
suspicious
plus if we find a village, we can...
oh, hello
This is always useful.
Well then...
Our pickaxe broke.
Which means I should stop (mining)
so, there we go
it's broken now
And we have 5 flint.
If we go outside, I assume it's morning.
there we go
oh, it's daytime
this might be a problem
let's cook iron for a bit
I think one is enough
our health isn't that critical right now
so we don't need to eat
We have a lot of gravel
Iron! Hallelujah!
We can make
a shield, but we don't have wood
Wait, did you need to have leather boots to walk on powder snow?
I'm not sure
Boom, we have a shield!
Wait, how do you even block with a shield?
wait
How do you block? How does this game even work?
the hell
Is the shield useless then?
That would be funny.
Wait... Oh, we can make some shears!
To quickly collect leaves.
We can make a pickaxe.
Do we even want to tough?
Okay yeah, we do
And...
I have to pause now.
What can we do with 2...
We can make a sword
C418, yay
wow, what the hell?
It's snowfalling
A lot of snow is falling, that's interesting.
I wouldn't have expected that.
That means it's dark outsie... wow
beautiful
OH MY GOD CREEPER
____ IDIOT. DON'T EXPLODE YOU IDIOT. FOR ____ SAKE!!!
eurghh, CREEPER!!!
that was horrible
On the bright side, we have snowballs.
huhah
we're putting these into the chest nicely
Okay, I would have never expected to see a snowfall.
World Of Warcraft
Beautiful
That's an interesting quirk about the bedrock edition. You would never see this in the Java Edition.
Where it's snowfalling and the leaves are white.
There is no such thing in Java Edition.
It would just snowfall and the leaves would have been green.
But that is a very interesting quirk about this version.
If you're wondering why I'm getting blocks, well this is the reason.
This snow here.
the uglies snow ever
wow, /\ E 5 ´´|´´ |-| E ´´|´´ | C
look, how many blocks we have now
we can
we can do stuff
There we go
Yeah, we have shears
\/\/e can shear stuff.
Oh, that's another difference compared to Java. You can't jump like this.
And while jumping, break the block.
that's powder snow
no, that's different snow
they're so similar, damn it
hard to differenciate
regular snow and powder snow
That CREEPER was a total moron.
Just exploded
What the hell? Why do CREEPERs explode like this?
I don't get it.
Oh.
Oh, I see
So, if I shift, I can block.
Icy
That's interesting
Once again, a difference compared to Java Edition
In Java, I'm pretty sure you right click to block.
But here...
You hold down shift
i.e. you sneak and when you sneak you can block
Which is pretty interesting.
Why was I stepping on a ladder, when the trapdoor was closed.
okay
This game is suspiciously broken.
The night is approaching, I'll just wait a bit instead.
* chompy chomp chomp *
We're going to heal in a moment.
wait
Was the snow falling through the ceiling?
Wait, if I'm in F5 mode, then the snow falls through the house.
the hell
let's look at these things
I don't see snow in first person.
But if I go here...
Wait, did the snowfall stop?
It didn't
If I'm in second person, then...
oh
It depends on the perspective!
Oh! I know what the problem is!
The camera touches the wall...
or is right against the wall.
And some kind of a boolean value, which controls whether or not to show snow particles...
...activates, because...
Because the camera is just a tiny bit outside the interior.
that's pretty interesting
The fox is going around our house again.
I mean, the arctic fox.
Foxes make weird noises.
I know this game is a bit more broken than Java, but...
It's still dark. I can see the fox.
The one that creeps around.
Once again near my house.
!WONS GNILLAF S'TI
Can I do something wit h this in addition to...
Oh, we can make this thing.
But it's generally pretty useless.
We can make a loom.
why not
But I wouldn't want to waste my string on the loom.
I would rather make a bow or something similar.
See, that's interesting.
The fox went past my trapdoor, but the ladder sound effect still played.
Because if you move accross the corner of the trapdoor, it still plays that sound effect.
I don't know why, but it just does that.
I really should find a few more sheep and kill them.
Or just use my shears!
That's actually a pretty amazing idea.
I can use shears to extract the wool and I even get 2 blocks of wool.
Plus, the sheep stays alive.
Pretty interesting idea.
Maybe I can lure them, no..
No, I can't, because I need wheat to lure them.
So that wouldn't fly.
It's dark outsid
???
We have a beautiful axe.
Foxes make interesting sounds.
.           __________________
.          |                           |
.O     _|   Oh, a skeleton! |
..|   _/  |__________________|
\|/
..|
./\
I could obtain bows from skeletons actually.
But they do use their bows, so that's a problem.
Oh, he stole a tree trunk!
Or the leaves.
Oh, hello spider.
Thanks for these things.
So, I have 4 strings now.
Theoretically I can make a bow and arrow.
We need a few more sticks.
If we want to make it... boom
that's a bow
Boom, ranged attack, people!
The problem is that we don't have arrows.
what? oh, we get XP
we didn't pick it up before
Where's...
oh, fox
oh, hello spider
hmmmm
twueaeauauaua
what the ____
Oh. That was a good strategy by the way.
just...
that creeper actually startled me
holy crap
huaehehe
OK
eagh
skeleton, where are you?
where are you, skeleton?
I want to smack you.
he tried to shoot me
it's really difficult to see a light gray thing on snow
Oh, here we go! I saw you!
There we go. Thanks for the arrows!
So I have...
multiple arrows now. I have 2 arrows and some bones.
Oh, I can tame a wolf.
If I really want to. With these bones.
I'm sure there are more skeletons.
Yeah, there are. I'm pretty sure I heard one.
hmmmm
There's a crazy snowfall period right now.
The CREEPER helped me find blocks, so...
If I see another CREEPER, then...
I'd rather not attack it.
Like, with a sword. But instead...
...shoot it with an arrow or something.
If you are really careful, then it isn't that...
I think that skeleton just despawned when I ran away.
hmm
Let's mine for a bit.
Because why not.
Let's find some more iron and stuff.
Like why not
oh, okay
oh my god, CREEPER
go away
I don't have more arrows.
What would be the safest way to get there?
hmm
there we go
we got rid of the CREEPER
Once again, a clever trick to get rid of this guy.
Okay, this is where the tough stone is.
So, we're not digging more down now.
Which we can use to mine everything except...
Hello!
Hello, iron!
How much iron? 10
That's more than before.
That's good news.
Even more iron!
huhuh
yo
We found some kind of a biome, but...
We have 22... things
Oh my god. Let's go inside.
And let's wait a while.
Let's cook these ones.
18... I think we need more...
yes
we got some XP
Where are our stuff cooked?
I can't speak, ooooooo
I wanted to make this.
That would be really useful.
And the second thing I wanted to make is this.
So that we can ignite stuff.
But what do we do with the rest? First, a pickaxe...
Let's first make some sticks.
Because it's useful in a lot of situations.
Second
I
Make myself a bit of... protection equipment.
That's a really useful thing.
Yeah, we can immediately equip.
So, I'm not naked anymore.
I have clothes on.
Let's organize some stone and stuff.
What else?
CREEPER?
Where's the CREEPER?
Let's take our sword out.
There's a CREEPER
I can see this green creature.
I'm hearing zombies
night
Green thing, come here!
CREEPER
Come on over here!
Hello, Zombie!
I can't block my thing
Come on, CREEPER!
Come on! Yes., come on! Come on, CREEPER!
Come on!
Come on! Come on, CREEPER!
Come on, CREEPER!
* the sound of silence *
Come, Come, Come!
Come on! Come on!
It didn't even drop gunpowder. What a scam this is...
What a scam. I really wanted som gunpowder.
Should we go into the Ice Spikes biome?
Maybe we can find an igloo or something...
hmm
Or maybe we're going to find a village?
Let's find out!
Maybe we'll find something useful.
I'm putting down some...
I should have made some boots earlier.
actually
I'm an idiot. I should have made boots.
I had the iron.
I should have made boots, come on!
eurghaaahhh
Okay, that's some parkour going on.
what a great parkour
I'm not that skilled in parkour, but...
I hurt myself again.
Pumpkins! Pumpkins, Yo!
Pumpkins!
Pumpkins! Let's carve a pumpkin!
Shall we carve a pumpkin?
Okay, it's snowfalling.
Damn it, I don't have food!
The only thing I have is that thing.
Yo, carved pumpkin, let's go!
Where's my axe?
A carved pumpkin
um
I think when it comes to coordinates, it should be near 0 0
That's where the spawn point usually is.
So, we shouldn't get lost.
But better safe than sorry.
Rabbit, I'm going to smack you.
Thanks for your meat!
Sorry about this, if you like rabbits! I had to do this!
I had no more food.
I really needed some food.
Okay, let's go in one direction.
forward
Let's see where we end up.
Hello, bear!
What did you drop? Just experience...
okay
we have a bear, but that shouldn't be an issue
This is ice spikes, a really amazing biome, but...
Wait, is there no cooldown, so I can just spam it?
No way
I can spam my axe, this is so OP.
wth
I can just spam my axe.
Like, what the hell.
Wait, is that a village?
Is that a village?
Or am I hallucinating?
Probably hallucinating...
or still...
Let's see
I think I'm hallucinating. This is not a village.
Or is it?
(Michael Stevens reference)
(that's what I just said, but previously it was in Estonian)
It is a village.
* children YAY sound effect *
Definitely
Look, these are wooden houses!
Holy crap, we found a snow village!
Is it a normal or an abandoned village?
Is that an igloo?
Hello!
oh my god
Oh, we have food!
Yo, we have food, we can sleep!
Yo, we have a bed!
yo
amazing
Do we have more chest with interesting things in them?
Let's have a look in the furnace, just in case.
Every place, where you can potentially store things.
Blast furnace may be useful, but...
Hello
What do you have?
nice
Beetroot seeds ooooooo!
Snowballs
What do you want?
Okay, you want papers...
okay
It's a pretty bad village, but at least it's better than nothing.
What do you want?
You want.. you want clay
We have more food!
No way!
this was the first part of my Minecraft
gameplay video
if you want to see more, please
let me know in the comments
if you liked this video, then press like
if you didn't like it, then press dislike
Thank you for watching!
Video creator  ​
Background music used
Software used        ​
YouTube channel
Thank you for watching!
© 2022 Markus' videos