Markus computer entertainment
Today, we are going to do something absurd.
And that is opening 6000 Google Chrome browser tabs.
You may ask - why?
Why would I do this?
One reason is, because I want to know what happens.
Tough I can tell you one thing - we are not going to use this laptop, instead we are going to use another laptop.
And the reason I'm not going to use this laptop is the following
To understand why I'm not using this laptop for the experiment
you need to take a look at this.
As you can see, this processor isn't that good.
The biggest problem with this laptop is that it has
In other words, this laptop basically screams when you even open 49 tabs.
Now imagine, if I opened 1000 tabs on this laptop.
Yes, this thing would explode.
Second problem, if we look at the CPU, it only has 2 cores.
Once again, a pretty slow processor.
For this experiment, we are going to turn off this laptop.
And we're going to bring out a completely new laptop.
Something which I haven't shown in any of my videos before.
boom
This is...
a laptop
okakay
So, first of all, how do you even open 1000 Chrome tabs?
The answer is simple.
We are going to use AutoHotkey scripts.
This is where the AutoHotkey folder is
And here is...
Okay, we accidentally opened the script.
But I wasn't an idiot.
We first need to press Alt+1
before anything happens.
So, what does this script do? It opens 1000 web pages.
Now, these 1000 pages, they aren't all unique.
You may notice, there's a loop.
So, do this 5 times times times times times.
If we count the lines...
Then it's 200 lines, exactly.
We are basically going to open
5x200 tabs, i.e. 1000 tabs.
Because 5 times 200 equals 1000.
So, with just a single key combination, we can open 1000 tabs.
And our AutoHotkey script is active.
The second thing I prepared
was a small Chrome extension, that shows the tab count.
I'm going to open OBS and see what happens.
Let's open OBS, start screen capturing, and open 1000 Chrome tabs - what could possibly go wrong?
Add
Screen Capture
Record mouse cursor, whatever
Start recording
As you can see, right now only 1 tab is open
and if we open more tabs, the number increases.
And if we open CPU-Z on this computer.
For some reason, I didn't think about opening this.
But as you can see, we have a Ryzen processor.
It's considerably more powerful than the one we had on the other laptop.
And it has 16 threads.
Hopefully it can manage.
And we have 16GB of random access memory.
And we have a NVMe Intel SSD.
We're ready to begin.
Let's put
Task manager always on top
And let's keep track of numbers.
I haven't tested this script before, so...
...it's possible it's not going to even work on the first attempt.
But let's see what happens.
ALT+1
And we are opening 1000 Google Chrome tabs.
The CPU usage is also pretty high.
Our extension is showing 65 tabs.
And our fans...
...started to...
Our video card is actually being used a lot
And WiFi as well.
Oh, hello! Oh, 1001 tabs open!
nice
Can we navigate between them? Yeah.
Pretty easily
Our video card is pretty hot.
71 degrees.
And the CPU is being utilized. Is OBS working?
No, OBS isn't complaining right now.
It's just recording.
But... okay, it seems all of the tabs have finished loading.
Are we ready to open 1000 more tabs?
Let's see what happens.
Okay, it's thinking...
Okay, it's still opening tabs.
Our mouse pointer is still smooth
And we can switch to OBS
Of course, we can't do much right now, because the browser window is grabbing the focus.
But we can hear fan noise.
Okay, the video card isn't that hot anymore.
Like it was before.
Okay, the browser window isn't grabbing the focus anymore.
Our recording is still going on.
okay
huh
very weird
okay
Seems like we could do something, but in reality, we can't do anything.
This text is something animat...
ueagh?
Okay, that's pretty weird.
There seems to have been a link...
Uh oh, something's happening.
We still have 1001 tabs open.
Our memory graph is just...
Compressed 0 MB
Seems like it can't really compress anything.
The disk usage is really high.
Yeah, we are using a big chunk of our laptop's resources, just to... ueagh?
apple.com opened up
Oh, 2001 tabs.
okay
This means we can open 1000 more.
Okay, let's see what happens.
Alt+1 starts this loop
hmmm
The available number is just jumping up and down.
Doesn't know if it's available or not.
Still 2001 tabs.
Okay, it's still opening tabs.
Still opening tabs. Okay, it's taking a while this time.
uhuhuh... okay.
Google Chrome showed the wait cursor for a bit.
hmm
And the video card usage is rising.
It's not really a video card, it's just some accelerated, integrated stuff.
But it's a Radeon, so yay.
Okay, OBS isn't complaining right now.
Oh, it stopped.
Stopped sending the command.
But... let's click on a tab.
Let's see what happens.
okay
Okay, it's hot.
Not that hot tough.
This laptop gets hotter, when playing games, so...
Everything seems to still remain pretty normal.
Still 2001, I'm not going to send the command until it says at least 3000.
15.8GB in use.
And 15.4GB is available to Windows.
Part of this goes to...
to the APU
hmm
wow
okay
The memory usage is always something like 99%.
So yeah, Google Chrome is a pretty infamous memory hog and we can totally see it here.
All of the commands have been sent to Chrome, so...
We're just waiting for it to change the picture.
Weirdly, if I move the mouse pointer onto this omnibox, then
I move, with the touch pad, to this field, then it changes
As if it is responsive, even tough I can't really do anything.
uhueagh?
Not responding
Let's wait.
Uh oh
Okay, we saw
the usage reduce a little bit
I have a feeling that there is memory swapping going on, it's just not showing it here.
Considering the disk usage.
So, there definitely is some swapping going on.
but... Uh oh.
So...
Google Chrome shut down
Which means, that...
The maximum verified...
...maximum number of tabs, that this laptop can open, in Google Chrome, is...
which isn't bad
considering, this computer has
considering it's a laptop
OBS has been recording this entire time
Next question, what happens if we restore these tabs?
Because, when Google Chrome gets terminated unexpectedly...
Then you are able to restore all of the tabs.
So, let's see what happens if we press Restore.
Probably nothing good. Okay, it stop resp...
Stops responding.
hmm
oh
Our memory usage hasn't increased a lot.
I wonder if it's even trying to restore anything.
Interesting, it's showing definition.net for some reason.
wait, is...?
The task manager is still responding.
Interestingly, no other program has stopped responding.
Once again, pretty interesting.
Oh, those were just my computer's specs that were open.
I assume it's going to open a new window and that'll contain all of the tabs.
I'm going to...
...charge my tablet, because its battery might run out.
oh
wait, how many? oh.
2540 tabs
Interestingly, RAM usage isn't that high.
So, all of these are just placeholders, or are they?
okay, so...
It seems like all of these tabs are sleeping, as you can see.
oh, my website!
Yeah, my website, people!
But let's see if we press the 1000 tab button yet again!
What will Google Chrome do next?
We've restored 2540 tabs.
Working
Oddly, memory usage and stuff like that is really low.
So, I'm curious what's happening.
hmm
We are rendering graphics right now, but... oh
oh
Chrome has stopped responding
Chrome started responding again
Maybe
We're still on 2540 tabs.
I don't see a lot of activity, which is suspicous.
Oh, that's an interesting graph to look at.
Oh
3540, hey guys!
Maybe our laptop can actually do something.
I thought 2540 was to upper limit, but...
Turns out it's not.
But once again, the fans are ramping up.
A little bit more this time.
Let's see if we can open 4540 tabs.
That's the question.
I pressed the 1000 tab button again.
hahahaha
okay
ouch
Google Chrome is unresponsive, close now.
If only I had an auto-clicker.
It seems like 3540 is the upper limit.
Okay, we didn't close Google Chrome.
It's possible it didn't open some tabs this time.
But our memory usage once again...
Pretty maxed out.
1..4 GB available
oh no
I can sort of put my pointer here and it shows the text selection cursor.
Okay, but it's delayed a little bit.
If I go here...
If I go over it fast enough, it doesn't even show up.
And if I go outside, you can see it shows the cursor outside the omnibox.
Let's see if we can switch to the Spotify tab.
Seems like everything's working right now.
The CPU usage also isn't that high, it seems.
But our clock frequency is still pretty high.
But not maxed out.
Can this laptop open 4540 tabs?
We need to wait to find out.
hmmm
Available... okay it was below 100 MB at some point.
The fans are spinning fast and the CPU usage... yup.
The clock frequency is over 4 GHz.
Which is... weuagh?
woah
4475 tabs, guys!
This site can't be reached
hmmm
I wonder how many websites are down because of my experiment
Not, the browser is really... eagh?
It's actually responding.
We can switch to other websites.
hhhoo
But it's really, really slow.
I think this means we need to open 1000 more tabs.
Because, as you can see, we can really easily...
...do stuff, so...
Let's press the Services button here.
And altough navigating between web pages is really slow, as you can see
it's still usable.
Whatever
Let's open 1000 tabs again.
It's probably a really bad idea...
But let's see what happens.
The fact that Google Chrome hasn't stopped responding is pretty amazing
I mean, closed unexpectedly
And Windows hasn't blue screened yet.
Fans, once again, are making noise.
And the tab count hasn't changed.
hmm
Let's try to switch to another tab.
CPU usage, not that extreme.
But the memory usage is most critical right now.
Has it stopped opening tabs?
Yes, it has.
I think it has.
So, Google Chrome is processing all of these tabs right now..
which we just opened
And hopefully...
something is going to happen
It's a pretty long waiting game.
Let's continue waiting until it does something.
Uh oh
yup
So..
It ended with this.
4475 was...
Was the upper limit right now.
Let's stop the recording right now.
And let's start a new recording.
just in case
The memory usage fell back to 1.7 GB
And... most of the memory is free.
Let's open Chrome again and see if we can restore all of these tabs.
5 minutes extra
Extra time
I can just wait and stay here.
Oh, hello!
Just out of curiousity...
...I'm going to give it another 1000 tabs.
If it crashes again, then we know why.
Can we reach 5475 tabs?
Who knows?
I have no idea.
(he didn't answer)
(popcorn?)
oh?
4476 tabs...
So it opened at least 1 tab.
During this time.
Oh, 5475!
Man, so it opened our LinkedIn page.
Actually, just the main home page for LinkedIn
okay, yes
We technically opened 5476 tabs, but...
But switching between them isn't really fast.
I pressed Ctrl+Tab something like 10 times.
But
Quick, draw!
Can we play this?
okay
uhm
oh, hot tub
I made a... okay it has...
Oh, I think it understood octapus
No, it understood these three. The ball, ocean, and this one.
I don't what I was drawing with these other ones.
Okay, I can switch between tabs with a pretty reasonable speed.
I have no idea what happens, when...
if we open 1000 more tabs...
Would you like to find out?
This is the very last experiment I'm going to do, before ending this video, so...
Holy Jesus
(fan spin)
(hums popcorn)
(more popcorn)
(hums the universal theme)
okay
So far 5475 tabs. I don't know where that 1 tab went.
Gone, forever
Why am I doing this experiment?
Why?
Why am I torturing my laptop?
Why am I doing this?
I don't know.
I'm tired.
I want to stop this experiment already.
5475 still
oh
5529 tabs, so far
newgrounds.com
that was the last page it opened
ohohoh
Stack Overflow home page.
6475 tabs open.
So, the question was, can my laptop open 6000 tabs?
The answer is... somehow, but...
But if I try to switch to another tab, then...
Yeah, I think it's pretty reasonable to say that I shouldn't open 1000 more tabs.
Plus, we cheated a bit, by restoring all of the tabs.
I bet, if we opened 1000 more, Google Chrome would just crash.
It's probably going to crash right now.
yup
jinxed it
At the exact moment I said Chrome was going to crash...
Guess what happened.
The browser window closed at the exact moment I said that.
So...
So, what was it... 6475?
Seems like that's the limit.
It's not capable of opening any more.
Out of curiousity, let's have a look at our browsing history.
history
and
Okay, it's showing multiple
But yeah, it's just repeating
all of the tabs we've opened
Our experiment was a success, I guess, somehow, maybe.
So, thank you for watching this absurd experiment!