Markus Computer Entertainment
The next distribution is more interesting.
Momonga Linux
You may ask - what the heck is Momonga Linux?
Good question
This is going to be interesting.
It's based on...
The most interesting part is that it isn't based on anything.
Momonga Linux
What operating system does it..?
2.6 or later
Start
And I forgot to choose the disc!
Let's go
okay
start system with basic video driver
Rescue installed system
Boot from local drive
Memory test
I want to know what Momonga is...
It's a flying squirrel.
That's what it is. Install
Install. We're installing.
I gave this VM 1 core.
Found local installation media
Okay, install or upgrade to disk
okay
that's okay
Re-initialize
Hostname
okay
We can choose our region
Root password
Use anyway
Interestingly, It realized it was a bad password.
so...
Use all space
next
okay
Graphical Desktop
Software Development
Web Server
Minimal
okay
And updates
Okay
This part has a lot of cuts, because they just stayed still for a while.
And updates
Next
Starting installation process
Congratulations, your Momonga installation is complete.
Please reboot to use the installed system. Note that updates may be available to ensure... blah, blah, blah
Reboot, I guess
It automatically ejected the CD, which is also a great plus.
oh, okay
Fancy startup sequence.
As you can see, you don't need a fancy startup image to make a cool bootscreen.
Welcome
okay
There are a few more steps to take before your system is ready to use.
The Setup Agent will now guide you through some basic configuration.
Please click the "Forward" button on the lower right to continue.
Create use... okay
network login
stuff like that
You don't really need to enable that, because VirtualBox does it automatically.
yay
We have language, sessions...
We can choose our session.
Gnome (don't judge the pronounciation here)
Xclient scripts
okay
KDE
Remote connection
Failsafe GNOME
Failsafe &Terminal
okay
What does it use by default?
There we go, this is GNOME 2.
And... hallelujah.
yay
as you can see...
yup, this is...
GNOME 2
It has a lot of built-in applications.
The question is, can we even install guest additons?
Okay, this might actually work.
uh, cool
Let's restart, I guess...
Then it might work. Restart.
Restarting...
Once again, nothing fancy.
On the startup and shut down screens.
Just a loading bar with text.
Which is pretty nice.
Yay, VirtualBox guest additions don't work!
Good to know!
Okay
Software update. Add or remove software, there we go!
This is where our package manager is.
Games
Cool
Newest packages, yo
package collections
Education
Multimedia
This is something I would install, for example.
Continue
okay
and....
For some reason, it doesn't work.
Fancy minimize animation.
What backgrounds do we have?
okay
wow
pretty okay backgrounds
Anyway
It seems to be a really old distro.
Can we play solit.. yeah we have Solitaire.
yay
best games ever made
sniff
wow
FreeCell
yaay
oh, freecell
I mean...
Simple Scan
But yeah
And this is an oooold version of Audacity.
yeah
The microphone doesn't work, because...
Anyway
No
Log out
We can choose a KDE session.
Just for this session.
okay, that's what KDE is
is this KDE 4?
I think it is.
An old version of KDE
KDE, what else there is to say. It's KDE.
But an old version.
KDE 4.5.3. That's not even that old.
But it's before 5.0.
Bouncy ball
wow
Very useful widget.
WHO THREW AN APPLE TO THE DESKTOP???
We can set the desktop wallpaper.
wow
Quartz. Yes.
eargh... wow
KDE
It uses the fade from Windows XP.
Which is interesting
anyyway
actions
okay, language
We have secure remote connection
X client script
yeah
Anyway, we're shutting down this computer and...
That's it for Momonga Linux.
That's it for Momonga Linux
We'll no longer take a look at Momonga Linux.