Hello! In today's video, I am going to be talking about what's been going on with my channel and what's new.
Topic 1
Handles
If you were unaware, then my YouTube channels now have handles.
Unlike channel names, handles can only contain numbers, letters, and underscores.
You're going to be soon seeing handles in comments in place of the username, channel page, YouTube search, and shorts (lol).
You can also use them to reference my channel.
Handles, which my channels use, can be seen on the screen.
Topic 2
Topic 1
Name change for secondary channel
The name for my secondary channel, mmaal x (markustegelane x), has been changed.
The new name is mmaal lite (markustegelane lite).
The new name reflects the lightweight content this channel produces.
The reason for this change was that the old name was confusing for viewers.
For example, the x in the old name was not related to number 10.
As a result of this change, the channel logo and overall graphics are changing.
The web page for that channel also gets a new URL, that is markustegelane.online/lite
In addition, the layout has also been updated.
Topic 3
Some of my earlier viewers might remember a batch file called "The Chatroom".
In case you don't, it was a chat-client, which was 100% made in the batch scripting language.
This batch file had some interesting features, such as sending Movement Batch maps, text files, and Farm Batch maps.
However, this batch file had a big limitation - it didn't work on the internet.
This meant that every chatroom was limited to a single computer.
Of course, it was possible to share the chatroom folder in a local area network and mount it on another computer as a network drive, but I didn't show you how to do it exactly.
The new version, which I am working on, allows you to make chats and join them all over the WORLD.
The old version used folders to store various chatrooms
But the new version uses HTTP requests and MySQL databases.
Like with Draw Batch, this batch file works independently
meaning all of the required dependencies are extracted automatically
Topic 4
End of Markus computer entertainment season 2
The first video on my channel this year, was the launch episode for the second season of Markus computer entertainment.
And I am planning to
end season 2 also this year.
Of course, this will not mean that I will not make any new MCE episodes next year.
Or some time later in the future.
Just that there'll be a longer pause until the next MCE episode is released.
This year, I am planning to release 2 more episodes of MCE.
First one is going to be about Samsung Dex, which is a desktop interface for Samsung tablets.
The episode ends with a twist, that leads to the final episode of the season.
But what's the content of the final episode for the second season?
The title is going to be "Windows XP and more [Markus computer entertainment special]"
You may be able to tell that this episode will not just be talking about an old and good operating system.
If you've been looking at and listening to the season 2 episodes carefully, you might foresee, what the last episode is about.
For those, who might not have caught up to what I just said, I'll give you a hint in the form of a word: CLUSTER.
Topic 5
The community tab
For the last topic in this info and news video, I want to talk about a YouTube feature that hasn't yet arrive to my channel - the community tab.
The community tab allows content creators to post text content, pictures, and polls, in addition to videos.
But why am I talking about a feature that isn't available on my channel yet?
The thing is that in the next following weeks or months, it's possible, that my channel is finally going to get a community tab, because YouTube finally decided to bring it to smaller content creators.
So far, it's been neccessary, in order to post updates to what's going on with my channel, to make a video or a blog post on my official channel blog
markustegelane-en.blogspot.com (for the english version)
However, making a video is a time consuming process and my subscribers aren't notified about a blog post.
The community tab would allow my subscribers to see what's going on with my channel.
They would also be able to vote in polls or just leave comments.
In case you are worried that this will end the info and news series, then don't, it won't happen.
If I think that it's very crucial information, then of course I am going to make a video.
But in the case of The Chatroom or MCE, for example, I would have only made community posts about both of them.
But I do plan to stop making blog posts after the community tab gets added.
The blog itself won't go anywhere
But I will just stop posting there, and I will only use it in extreme situations, such as when I lose access to my YouTube channel.