20 minutes earlier
Okay, I clapped.
He he hello!
In today's video we are taking a look at gnusmaS Dex.
Now, what is gnusmaS Dex?
And the answer is actually pretty simple.
gnusmaS Dex is a desktop interface for gnusmaS devices.
Anyway, let's talk about the technical details of the making of this episode.
First problem
How do we get a picture from here to there?
To the capture device.
The battery on this phone is empty
eeeeeeeempty
Which I am not happy about at all.
Type-C, as you can see
It'll convert it to HDMI
HDMI cable!
We are going to connect this HDMI cable
Great! Next we are going to connect this adapter...
...with the tablet
Oh, nice!
Next we need to connect the HDMI cable somewhere ( ͡° ͜ʖ ͡°)
If you are asking where, then the answer is vi..
Now we connected the capture device to our computer.
And if we look at the screen, then
papababaaa, we have a picture.
So, the next part of the video is...
Subtitle error
oh nice
The first question you may have is...
...how do I enter Samsung Dex?
Because, by default, you're in tablet mode.
This is where you can see your apps and stuff.
The answer is simple. You open the notification area.
And then from here, you open Dex.
But we've reached the topdesk.
Now this brings...
...us to the next question.
If we want to, we can continue using our device using the touch screen.
But the interface isn't that good for that.
I'm going to turn on some stuff first so you can see what I touch.
Okay, very good!
Next we need to connect some devices.
This is something I'll have to record again, so...
Yes.
Shall I stop or not? Probably not.
Let's take a look at our mobile device.
Let's connect our keyboard.
For this, we need to make sure Bluetooth is enabled.
As you can see, Blutooth is turned on.
Next
Let's bring in our device.
Here it is.
Let's turn this keyboard on
and it should connect automatically
because it knows that the tablet was the last device it was paired with
And we have a keyboard
Next question...
Who's idea was it to shift Escape to Fn, like why?
Uh, next question...
How do we connect a mouse?
One thing you can do is use the included S-pen.
But that isn't ideal.
So, let's bring in the Bluetooth mouse.
Boom! It's a mouse!
Subtitle error
joj
jooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooj
Let's see if we're lucky.
I wasn't lucky
And now...
magic
We can use the mouse
Ohhhh
I know why it didn't open.
Because if we do a single click...
then nothing happens
we can move this icon
and the cursor changes accordingly
But we have to double click
That's really weird.
Because, my brain says this is a smartphone folder.
You touch it.
If you click it once
Nothing happens
Because you selected it.
And if we right click, we can only remove.
So, if we double click, it opens the app.
um
Okay, so here's our Chrome OS Flex video.
We can watch it!
I want to see if this works. If I open My Files...
And let's drag and drop one of them to a folder, such as... Internal Storage.
Documents
And let's drop one of them...
It doesn't work.
How sad...
I would have hoped for this to work.
Network storage
Opening Galaxy store for a required update...
Oh, we have to update.
Thank you, gnusmaS!
For nothing.
Network storage
We can connect with our desktop
And copy some files from here
Oh, here...
...in this gnusmaS app, you click once.
Copy here
Okay, this thing...
um
[sound effect from the Windows Eerie Autumn sound scheme]
Yea, I'm not going to explain that.
You can pane windows.
But you can't put them in corners.
which is
"The connected device is being charged through USB"
Are you talking about the adapter?
Let's make a desktop icon for an app, for example...
EE Radio
To make a desktop icon, just add to homescreen...
And boom, here it is!
We can freely move icons.
Screen magnification, what is this?
Oh
Maybe for a video, this is better.
Because you can see better.
Oh, we can just take a screenshot like that.
It's a pretty simple interface really.
Let's open a game.
Yeah, I don't have games here.
Sad
THANK YOU ADS, BECAUSE OF YOU, I CLOSED THE GAME!
YOU ALWAYS MAKE ME FRUSTRATED, MOBILE ADS!
Okay, I won't play this game anymore because of that.
Let's play another game, until we see an ad.
Oh, I'm so good at this game.
Guess what, they're showing ads!
I don't want ads!
I don't want ads. I will close your game, if you show me ads.
Probably one of the reasons I don't play many Android games anymore.
Markus' stuff integration, does it even work?
Probably not.
nyeaah
But I know that Chrome remote desktop definitely works, so...
Now...
Yes, it does work, but...
Let's just say that this app assumes you have a touch screen and doesn't work very well because of that.
If we move the pointer, then nothing happens.
I wanted to try something, does...?
Samsung Internet
A browser we all know and love
.
jokes
Let's go to our website!
Wow, we're on our website!
We can see stuff.
All of this fits on the screen, but if we open the report...
Yeah, we can touch.
And move this table.
Hey, we're making this videooooo....
Yeah, I suspected something like this might happen.
Let me know in the comments, which one was your favorite profile picture/logo.
And 2021, I think I did a bit more than change the english name of the channel.
For example, I already recorded the Enso OS video in 2021.
Fun fact: Everything is pre-recorded.
So that I can edit them something like 8 months later.
The recording date might sometimes be really early.
These are the new settings you can change, which are really touch friendly, as you can tell.
The next thing I wanted to show was settings.
You may say - but you already did.
The answer is I didn't show everything.
If we open Samsung DeX, we have multiple options here.
Start automatically, when Book Cover keyboard is connected.
Now, book cover keyboard
What's book cover keyboard?
Let me show you
So yeah, it's a keyboard and cover combo basically.
Which costs way too much, which is why I don't have it.
Start automatically, when HDMI is connected.
Connect wirelessly
In case your TV supports connecting with Samsung devices.
Of course, I can't imagine what the latency might be.
Probably not very good.
Automatically hide taskbar.
I wonder... yes
It hides the keyboard automatically.
TASKBAR****
Font size we already took a look at... screen.. oh font size...
Yeah, we can change it.
We already took a look at screen magnification. Wallpaper
um, okay
We can change the lock screen and home screen backgrounds.
Fun fact
All of this is only applied Samsung DeX.
So, if you leave DeX, you'll be reverted to the previous background you had before.
But in Samsung Dex, this wallpaper is retained.
Next, keyboard.
So, if you are using a physical keyboard, which we are doing now, then we can show a virtual keyboard if we want to.
Here's a bunch of boring keyboard settings.
But next interesting thing - cursor.
We can change different things about it.
We can change its speed, so if it's really slow...
Of course, we can also change the DPI of our mouse already.
We can also change the speed of the scroll bar, so if we scroll know, it's just straight up and down...
And if it's slow, we have to scroll for a bit.
We can change the color of the cursor and this is the default setting.
We can also make it comically large.
Let's make it that big.
or that large
Black cursor, which I really don't like, because they don't use a white outline, like come on?
At least give it a white outline, so that I can see it on a black background.
So, if I turn on...
Let's turn on dark mode and see what happens.
It's basically invisible!
I can't see anything!
Samsung, what the funk?
You can't see anything!
Yellow cursor, if that's something you like.
Red..
The pastel colors also aren't the best, I just use the white one.
Middle button - function determined by the app
I don't know how many apps actually utilize the middle button.
Anyway, normal stuff here, but
if we go to advanced features, we already took a look at Samsung DeX
And open labs
We can do various things.
Multi-window for all apps
That's something we already had turned on.
Stuff we normally have on tablets
if we swipe down.
We can turn off the tablet.
and
Finder, what does that do, I haven't used it.
It doesn't search for files.
Sad... das... I would have hoped.
Next thing to try...
Is to lock the device.
And as you can see, we have to enter a password.
But that is what the lock screen looks like. Pretty fancy.
Let's enter a password.
And if we enter a password, we're back at the home screen ,so...
That's pretty self-explanatory.
Cont̵act̵ us, what̵ is t̵his?
so̴me kind o̴f fe̴e̷dback
h̷e̵h̶e̴h̶e̷h̵e̴
í̷͙r̴̪̉o̶̡̅n̶̢̉ÿ̸̼́
i̴͔̫͓̿̓̌̚͝ͅr̷̤̩͒̉̕o̷̳̠̻̊̓̀͂n̶̲̳͙̳͕̜̙͇̳͍͇̖̰͉͈̲̾̇̑̚y̶̛̟͎̲̞̬͖͐̑̾̆̈́
b̶̨̛͖̘̙̺̪̖̺̟͈̰̟͎̹͙͔̩̩͔̻͉̩̘̤͖̟͔̱͂͗̅͒̀̔̈́̓̾̓̇́̑̅͑̆͒̿̈́̌͊͑̇̎̓̽͘͝͝͝͝ͅu̶̢̡̢͎͎̦̺̩̱͙̙̹̣͚̝͎͇̱̪͍͔͛͂̎́͂̽̊̈́̏̌̑͋̚͘͝͝͝t̷̨̢̻͈̝͈̫͙̪͙̝̦̭̖̜̘̮̞̤͉̗̻̰̟̱̩̙͙̟͙̗̤̊̐͑̈́̑̏̾̏̏̓͂̿̊̍̊͒̃͗́́̾̈̊͊̒̇̃̃̑́̄̕͝͝ ̵̢̢̗̘̞͙̞̝͓̔̾̿̊̇̒͌͆̈́̐̏̄͐̓̋̏̏̆͌̈́̍̈̀̊̓̋̚̕͘͝͠͠l̴̛̛̺̮͚͈̲̪̣͚̦͑͒̉͒̀͛̐̉̃́́̓̃̋̎͒̈́ͅę̶̢̡͓̳̞̗̘̘͖̦̬̞̞̺̤̣̳̯̝͚̮̠͇̖̠͙͖̬̙̮͔̮̤̪͈̂͌̈́́̐̐̓͊̈́̐̾͂̽̍̇͌̒̑̿͘̕̕͜͜͠͝t̴̟̲̦̠̝̹̥̹͍̦̗̩̱̣̥͔̣̖̳̎͐̎̒͆͑̔́͊̂̌̌̽̄͊̋̀̔̑͐͊͗̎̕̕͘͜͜͝'̶̛̗̜̠̺̭̻̻̦̠̪͋̈́̄̈́̌̋͌̍̅̚͠͝s̵̡̧̛̖͖̲̞̠̮͎͎̜̥̺͚͔͕̘͍͊̄̈́̈́͒̇̀̀̂̍̐̓͋͂̾̎̊̉̎̉͛̾̾̏̕̕ͅ ̶̢̨̛̻̜̊͒͊̃͗̑͋̈́̕̕̚͝͠͝q̷̧̨̨̢͎̳̭̺̱̟̮͙̝̯͎͚͙̮͍͎̩̪̳͈̻̜̝͕̠͕̪͉̪̪̰̻͙͐̇̔̉̆͌̀̒̎̈͗̃̽̔̚͠u̵̢̦͍̭͉̥̺͕̗̖̹̺͍̦̺̩̦̥̖͙͔̼̱̼̜͇͔̝͖̱͙̮͒̇̄̇̽͆͜ͅi̶̧̛̼̟̞̼͕͇͙̫̦̙̺͙̎́̃̅̍̉̐́͊͑̄̇̔̎̍̒̂̾͋͂̀͘͘̕̚͜͝ͅt̵̰̝͕̟̞̥͊̂́͑͊̈̈́̐̎̃̎̔̅́̋̉̒̊ ̶̨̢̢͍̗̻̥̫̮̤̠̦̙̩̾̃͂̏̓̂͆̂̈̔̏͊͋̓͘͝͝ͅḐ̶̧̨̧̤͇̮̼͎̞̻̟̤̦̤̯̟͇̼̤̦̺͔̖̭̙̤͂̌̍̔̈̐́͋̾̋̚͠ͅḛ̷̢̗͙͓̱̘̥̦͙̜͎͓̯͈͈̦̘̭̻͍̱͇̭͎̱͇͂̑͒̽͊̌͘͘͜X̴̺̦͙͚̟̗̼̱͓̳̜̰͎̭̳̦͇̣̖͔̺̻͓͖̪͈͖́̑̊̽̍͊̽̚͘͜͜͠ ̵̛̰̞̱̜̱͔̮́̍̐̒̑͌̐̅̀̀͊̓̌̄͗͐̄̂͠m̵̢̨̢̤̗̲̰̹̠̖͓͚̀͊̒̂̑̉̏̑͗̉̿̄͋͛̆̓́̋̔͆̈́͒̀̃̀̑̀͛̌̌̃͠͝ͅͅơ̶̰̖̋̈́͋̐͋̐̅͆̾̽̈́̚͠͠d̶͖͍̗̗̱͇͔͂̋̿̍̏̑͒̑̌̽̆͑̿̓̌́̌̔͐̄͋̀́̕̚ę̶̢̡̧̛̩̰̰͔̰̦͙̟͇̠͎̟̮̩͇̙͓͙̪͔̊̄̀̉͋̿̎̌̒̃͆̉̑̃̚͘͠ͅ.̷̲̦͕̟͔̩͎͕̘̣̥̼̼͖̺̮̭̅͗͋̎̏̀̐̆̀́̂͋̍̈́̈́̅̈́͑̋̚͠͝͝.̵̧̢̢̼̝͖͇̮̪͍̥̳͕̖̘͍̥̘̜͕͔͕̗̯̙̺̝̪̀́̑̾͑̀̈́́͑̽́̈́̊̽͒̋͒̄̐̔̽̽͂̽͛̕ͅͅͅ.̵̨̧̨̗͖͎̼̗͓͖̜̠̦̩̼̜̻̗̥̖̫̬̻̗̰̺̳̦͎͙͉̮̣̫̞̠̥̇̿̂̋̈́̃͌̑̎̈͛̀͌̉̀̃̚͝ͅͅ
N̸̨̢̢̡̛͓̩̼̮̱̣̬͎̪̰̗̮̣͉̦̠͓̮̞̺̲̮̞͕͕̤̭̬̩͙̓́͂͛̂͛̄͂̓̿̒́̾͂̇͗̊̑̄̑̚͜͜͝͝ẽ̴̢̡̞̖̖̤͍̰̤̙͖͎̦̺͔̳͇̞͚̏͋̄́̑̆̓̈́̐͘̕x̵͍̘͍̟̫̫͈͇̌͗͋̾͂̀͌͌̿͑̽̐t̷̡̨̛̪͍͚̮̱̫̝̟̪̣̱͇̩̟̮̤̯̩̩͚͈̭̬̀̌̈́̓͊̈́͐͛͑̽̿͋̎͛̔̈́̔̋̽͂́͂́̍̌̿̀͌̋̏̃̈́́̕̕͘̕͜͜͜͠ ̴̧̢̨̛̛͙̻̱̤͎͙̲͓̣̹̥̟̖̳̺̮̜͖͖͕̲͓̥̾͋͐̽̈́͋̀̅̈́̀̆̆̂͛̆̓͂̂͂́͋̂͌̏̾̋̃͑̀̚̚͜͠͝͝͝v̸̡̢̧̢̻̝͇̱͉͙̳̬͖͓͖̟͕͕͕̳̰̩̺̟̙̣̳͔̗̟͚̀̀̿̇̔į̴͚̙̺͓̮̽̓̽͋̇̾̍̎̀͌͋͒̈́̔͑͐̔̋̉͗͑̽̊̌͘̚͠d̷̦̭̺̳̻̜̖̻̠̬̠̋̈́̉ͅę̶̧̹͓̬͍͔̬̙̲̻̝̮̝͕̯͍̝͇̩̜̣͚̃̃̍͑̋̑͂́͌͗̄o̵̡̫̙͚̤̙̯̜͔̙̹̹̯̫̗̜̗̯̫͛̆̉̊̇̈͌͒̋̊̋̾̌̔̈́͗̈͑͐̅͑̾̈́̉͗̀̕̚̚͘̕̚͝:̶̧̛̮̦̝̼̦̍̒̏̈́͊̓̽̊̏́̔͗̿̕̚ ̴̢̛̠͓̝̲̰͇̞͚̘̖̫͓̦̻̹̘̗̖̪̻̟͓̼͚͕̱͔͚͎͓̀̓͗̉͂̉̆̾͂̊̄̆̈́̈̇̏͗͋͋̓̌͋̇̃́͌̉͊́͂͆͊̔̓͌͠͝͠W̶̡̡͍̫̜̟̠͕̞̙͉͚̿͒̆̾̎͋̉̆͘i̸͉͔͌̿̽̆̔̉̓̇̚ǹ̶̨̛̺̥̯̥͚̟͚̘̙̦͕̈̏͌̓̇̉̈́͋͑͑̾͒̅̈́̅̋͛͋̉͛̌̃̓̚̚̚̕̚̕͝d̷̠̀̌͋̐͑̀̆̆̚õ̴̡̢̨̳̺͈̖͎͍̥͉̪͎̬̝̹̗̦͇̭͖͉̜͕̮̩̭͎̞̪̟͙͛́̍̆̐̿̾̉̾̋̐w̷̛̼̓̓̃̑̃̈́͌͋͆̉̕͠s̶̢̡̡̞̦͓̠͉̱͙̬̲̪̝͎̞̱̙̖̖̦͉͖̟̩͖̫̘̼̠̩̝̘͑̄ ̴̨̢̡̧̛͇̮͔̙͙̲̰͉̻̼̫͖̠͚͔̖͉̫͖͓͚͓̼͉̜̘͇̰̤̻̠̑͊̒͂́̍̈́̏̔̍̃͊̆͋̓̀̌́̽̅̃̓͌̋̏́͘͘͝͝͠ͅX̵̧̡̧̨̛̰̭̺͚͇͚̰̝̖͈͖̦̖̘̥̺̮̗̘̠̜̮̺̾̔̓̀̉̈́́̎́̚̚͠ͅͅͅP̷̡̻͍̟̦̦̣̗͇̅́͌̊̈́͘ͅͅ ̵̨̡̢̧̢͙̰̬̰̗͔̦͓͕̻̥͇͇̙͕̜̬͙̺̻͍̘̹̭̪͚̖̺̯͛͌͐̿̏̋̄̆̀͆͒̿̀͑̐̒̌̽̽̿͂̆͗̂̚̕͝͝͝a̴͖̱̖̭̲͔͍͕͔̪̣̤̬͚̳̺̞̮̯͗̀̒̑̊͒͜͜n̷̨̡̢̢̨̡̛͍̲̹͉̠̗̼͔̳̤̜̩̲̗̮͈͖̭̬̠͈̝̐̈́̿̌̽̔͒̌̉̃̀̆̍̄͛͆̄̀̂̅̌̒͋̒̕͘͜͜͜ͅd̵̢̡̦̝͉͈̠̱̬͍͔̞̤͙̘͉̲͉̺͎̦͖̈́͗́͋̿̋̌͑̔̓̽̉͋̈̓̔͘̚͜ͅ ̸̡̡̨̡̳̖̥͎̣͙̥̠̹̬̰̱̱̯̦͓̻̯̝͚̗͓̘̆̀̉̊͐̈́́͑̂̀́̄̓͌̐̾͛̆̈͊̈́͝ͅm̸̨̢̨̧̡̨̛̗͔̖͉͔̥̹̹̜̤̟͍͉̱̞̮̩̞͎̰̦̫͋̈́̅̅̀̊́͒̑̀̒̌̉́́̐̌̂̀̃̾̍̈́͘͝͝o̸͚͚̪̯̗͔͓̪͎̗̙̰͓̙͚̟̼̙̦̳̼͓̪̒̃͋͐͗͌̓̆͜͝ͅr̸̛͈̯͚̖̠̹̥͈̝̓̈́̀̓͐͂̉͗͂̃̈́͌́̑̉͌̄̈́̅̂̇̂́̌́̇̀͗͠͠ͅe̵͇̻̽̄̃͋̃̉̓͑̎͑̓͆̌͂̌́̽̿̑̑̐͊̀̀̃̌̃͗̚͘͝͝
Ṋ̶̨̢̢͎̤͍̜̲̞͕͖̘͕̙̫̰͆̇͒͂͒̀͗̍̂̓́̋͊̂͝ę̶̧̧̟̲͚͙̮͑̑̽̚͘͜ͅx̴̤̤̟̭͖͓̱͍̲̟̆̃̆̈̇̓̓͐̈́̀̏̃͆͗̍͑̽̂͘͝͠͠t̵̨͇̜̗͎̘͊̂̂̌̾͑͘̕͜ ̸̢̡̨̲̘̜̝̦̠͈͚̺͎̦͖̫͉̗͊͂̊̈̑̓͛̎̊̔̈̈̔͘̕̕ͅv̴̛̛͈̤̙͓̣̦̖͓̭̲̦̲̠͉̿̊̈́̓͂͆̓͒̓͒ͅi̵̡̛͖̩͕͎̙̜̳͓͉̠͔̪̱͛̍̾̔̐̍̏͑̀̊͋̍̀̍͝d̷̨̢̡̙̥̪̦͉̫̪̮̥̥͗̔͑͛̕ͅȩ̶̜͙̝̭̳͙͇̖̖̤̂́͂̈́̓̈́̄̈́̄͋̀͐̚̕ó̴̡̤̽̑̂̑͋͊̆̑͂̊́̎:̵̡̠͙̦͇̱͙̲̗̪̜͔̱̖̱͔̘̘̼̓̂͊͂̄̀ ̶̛̛̖̟̣͈͛́͋̏̍́́̆̉̔̇̋͐͋̑̋̈́̈́͋͘͝͝W̵̧̳̦̮̗͇̯̠͔̲̙̾̊̎͒͋̀̿̋i̵͍͒̀̑̈́̂̈́̉͛͑̈́̆͐̋̈́͗̾̚̕̕͠͝͝ņ̴̟̯͕̭̪͊̓̆ḋ̸̢̛͔̱̯͉̳̰͈͔̐̆̒̈̀̈̿̌̆̈̂̈̇ǫ̵̨̤͚̼͇̘̭̮̰̺͓̝͎̠̯̩̩̤̮̻̞̪͐̇͒̈́͐̽w̶̖̠̄̉̈́͌́͒̅̒̆͐͑͌͒̕͘̚͝͠ş̸̥̙͉͉͎͕͓͔͔̱̖̗̥̝̱̃̍̀̾̔̈́͐͆͑̊̚̕͜͝ ̷̡̧̛̤͙̲͉͓̠̜͔̖͈͙̠̙̣͖́͂̈́͊͛͐̔͗̍͛̀͆͌̕͘͜͝͠X̶̡̼̝̞̩̬̞̰̹̜̩̬̺͖̹̀̎͆̈́̋̀̇̓̉̿̆̕ͅP̴̡̢͍͖̯͇͖͔̟̰̜͖̙̜͎̰̪̹̱̪̞̎͜͜͜ ̷̧̢̡͕̺͔̺̙̠̤͖̘̖̩͕͎̥́͊̍̎͒͗͂͌̉͒̽͋͂͊̆̄͌͝a̷̛̛͈̠̳͍̞̝̬̩͑̎̑͐͒̓̌̅̅̽̊̄̇̂̆̊̓̍̎̈́͝͝ņ̴̨̖͓̙̯͕̏͆̾͋̀͌͗̾͌̏̅̽̐̊͆͌͝ḑ̶̡̡̡͉̤̭̪̮͍͚͚̹͎̼͓̫̗͓̉́̒͌͘͝ ̴̢̨̛͍̣̱̼͍͓́͆̇̽̑̈͋̉͛̉͂̇̈̔̇̒̚̚͠ͅm̶̢͖̳̤̳̰͍̻̥̮͍̪͕̖̻͓̑̽͛̆̄̊̀̒̈̽̓̒̉̑͆̀̐͐̕̚ͅo̶̱̺̜̮̿̉̂͗̓̿͆͐͂̈̆̂̒̅̆̎̊̿̔̚͘̕ͅͅr̷̛͙̱̙̪̝̗͖͓͎̹͙͙͖͙͓̖̐͊̐̊̌̒͜e̸̡̢̤̤̦͍̟̥̜̮̺̖̣͎̥̬̎
N̶̤͙̿̐̃̀͆ë̴̦͚̬̬̠̣́̌x̴̫͈̬͙̟̙͈̐t̴̞͝ ̵̨̘͙̤̺̥̬̌̽͌͐̐͂́ͅv̴̧̮͇̹͍̤̬̻͑̌̿̀̉̈͗̇̿͋͘͘͝i̴̡̡̨̲̱̻̘̭͖̼̠̯̾̓́̃̂̌̊͌̊̕̕͝d̵̨̜͕̞͙̫̚ͅe̷̤̹͙̪̞̗͝ͅo̶͉̱̤̲͚̖̞̲̭̱͛ͅͅ:̵̡͉̟̭̤̥͎̭͒̈͋̓͜ ̵̻͈͈̥͛͛́̎̑̓͛̔̚̚̕͝W̸̠̆̈́̋̏̓̈ḭ̵̧̦͎̣̆́̍̍̿͊͆͗̄̃n̸̟̱̮͑̊͊͆͛͊̋̕͠d̵̥̩̪̘̩̃̈̒ơ̶̧̨̡̧͈̦̹͉̖͎̗͊̐̈́̒͂͑́͘ͅẘ̵͈͔̦ͅs̷̢͕͉̣͚͈̖̒͌̔̆̐͠ͅ ̸̣̘̗̰̭̰͋̔́͠͝X̷̛̪̻͈͑͛̽̎̐̊̔̆̒̓͜P̷̡̜̗̞̳̠͎͕̻̭̟̞̓̈͑͛̓͊͗̕ͅ ̷̛̗̓̀̅̓̈͂͗͛̚̕͝a̵̢̘̪̦̓́͐͐̃ͅn̷̙̘̼̤̐̀͂́͒̔̌̂͝ḑ̶̡̼̺̠͇͕̪̲̦͛̇͝͝ ̵͇̙̬͇̏͂̆m̵̡̹̼̮̙̖̯̤̤͓̓͗͒̐̆̚ͅọ̴͓͖̤̌́͒͌̋̎́r̸̨̛̛̳̙̭̘̥̹͙̙̩͗̊̎̊̂̂͐͊ȇ̵̻̻̫̙͊͑̀̑͆̅̄͘͝͠
N̸̥͔͈͍͒͗͛̋ë̸̩́͆͊͂̒̉̊̕̚x̵̩͍͎͎͌t̷̡͎̺̩̝̳͕̤͐͋̀ ̵̢̳͙̬̟͊̋͛̑͌̑̓̊v̴͉̫̥̜̒̿̏͆̆͂̃̚i̸̪̽͌d̷̗̬͈͖̻̥̹͒͑́̈́̏̀̊͝ȇ̵̡̘̩̪͓̠͖̐o̴̧͎͉̞̣͊:̶̛̠̭̲̀̌̍̈́̈ ̸̠̤͎̱͎̖͛́́̃̄̃͋̈͘W̵̨̫̓̈̌̊͗̀̈͝i̷͕̮̿͑̀̑̒̀̆͑͑ň̵̡̰̰͔̟̯̻͔͗͆͋̕d̷̟͙̈́̀̊̉̌͒̆ȍ̵̧̻͚̼̝̟w̴̢̯̃s̸̨̧̯͍̬͉̩̠̝̀́̒̈̐̏̐̾ ̴͇̤͈̪̹́̈́̐̓̕X̵̗̬̦̲̥̟̾̍͜P̴̛̜̪̙̞͚̠͙̫̘̃́̂ ̷̠̔á̷̧͍̲͚̜̐n̵̨̨̠͍̩̤̟̈́̽̆ḑ̷̝̠͍͍̦̗͔̆͐̌̉͜ ̶̭̗̖̝̻̫̀̿̄͂ͅm̵̨̗͚̊̓̚o̸͖͇̝͊͌͒͑̔͠r̸͍̲̺̊̿̉̓̕e̷̤̓̀͊
Ǹ̵̡̻͎̜͎̦̳͙͗͑e̶̗͉͚̙͉̖̅̒̌̅͂̉͠ͅx̶̧̢̱̤̥̳̰̟̼̞͍͕͉͎̝̯̽́̀̉̒̽͛̿̆̕͜͝͝t̵̢̨̝̩͖̰̖͈͚̘̭͆́̒̒̀ ̶̩̣̥̘̖̞̗̽̈͒̓̀̉́͂̚v̶̨̬̲̖͚̞͙̳̘͆̇̃̿͌̉́̑͛̍̀̽͌̚̚͝͠ͅĩ̶̡̗̺̠̺̺͎̥͚̤͜d̶̡̢̥̹̘͍̟̞̻̳͍̤͍͚͒̓̃͗̆͋͆̈́̚͜ͅé̷̤͚͓̼̻̜͍̹o̶̗͉̝̅̓̆̈́̍̏̓̊͗̌͊:̵̡̜͙̘̱̭̑̐̊́͘͝ ̷̧̛̰̪̘̖̺͍̘́̏͗͊̾̎̍̈́͑W̸̢͍̖̣̦͎̻̥̟͈̜̳̰̰̅̕i̶̢̧̡̢̳͚͎̣̫̺͚̥̟̮͂n̵͖̫̝̭̟̲̙̟̭̥̝̣͆̈̂̋͝͝d̶̬̯͕̭͋͗̀̇̀̄̆̐̒̀̐̉͜͠o̴̢̢̬͕̮̜̞̻̔̍̉̎̆͝͝͝ͅw̶͎̖̹̬̰̦̞̓̇̏͂̄͛́͂͑̀̚͘s̷̢̢̖̗̲̮̤̼͙̭͕̩̦̟̘̀̂͊̊̇̀̈́̈́͒̐̓͑̂̔̋ͅͅ ̷̢̛͓̯̭͙͉̼̞͓͌̎̇͂̾̊̄̋X̷̧̧̛̰̔̀ͅP̴̛̲̠̞̹̤̾̀̀̓̾́̎̈́̈́̓̕͝͠ ̴͙͚̥̺̳̍̎̐̈́̔͛̃͐̈a̷̟͓̱̩̦̘̥̻̿̽̒̑̈͌̓̕̕͠n̴̛͔͌͑̿̒̄̚͝d̴̨͎̩̪͎̪͈̙̝̼̟̲̝̜̥̫̹͊̐̃͆̒̅͂̃͐̀̔̇̚ ̷̗̯̞̈́̃̀̓͐̋͊̀́̅̒̊̔̓͋͠͝m̶̛̛͙͚̘̉̅͊̀́̉͒̎̍̀̚͝͝͝͝ȯ̶̼̩̠̙̝͙̤͇̼͉̟͆̓̎͛̒̐͑͛͝r̴̙̯̫̳̭̈́̽̀̉̓͠e̶̢̢̡̢̦̻̙͓̦̞̮̞̳̪̬͒̅̊͐̐͋̑͘