If you try to install Movie Maker, you may see the following
error code
Open Settings > Time & language > Region & Language
Click "Add language"
Find language "English (United States)"
Make sure to check "Set as my Windows display language"
Click the "Install" button
Wait until the language pack is installed...
Click "Log out" and log back in.
Retry installing Movie Maker...
Movie Maker is now installed and 100% functional
Now you can rever the language back. Go to Settings > Time & language > Region & language
From the "Windows display language" dropdown menu, select your original language. Log out and back in.
Despite the language change, Movie Maker is still in English.