Hello, I'm Markus from MarkusTegelane
Today I am going to show you how to install Linux Mint
Using only a flash drive and a computer.
The first step is to download Linux Mint.
Okay, so the first step is of course to download Linux Mint.
So, go to the home page of Linux Mint.
Click "Download"
And you have 3 different versions available.
Since the laptop I'm installing it to isn't really powerful, I'm going to use the MATE version.
I'm going to download it.
And let's choose a mirror that's closer to us.
And the file is downloading.
While our operating system is downloading...
It's a good idea to talk about a software program we're going to use to make a bootable USB.
So, we're going to download the Rufus program.
And this one has already finished.
If we now connect our flash drive.
And start Rufus.
And give the program administrative privileges.
Then we can see our flash drive.
And from here we can choose our ISO file.
But since our ISO file is still downloading, then...
it isn't ready yet.
Okay, the download has finished.
Now, to make our USB bootable, we need to "burn" the ISO to it.
For this, we're going to...
...choose our Linux Mint iSO file.
Persistance is for when you want settings you've made on the USB to remain after a reboot.
You can leave partition scheme and target system as is.
If you have an older computer, that doesn't detect your USB correctly, then this option might help you.
And if you can't see your USB drive, you can check this option.
Format options
You can change the label if you want.
Choose a file system. FAT32 is fine in this case.
and
Quick format. I don't want custom icon and stuff.
So, if the USB drive is correct, we are ready to begin.
So, now you'll have the option to either write the image in ISO or DD mode.
Basically, choose ISO mode and if that doesn't work, choose DD mode.
If you get a message like this, just click "Yes".
This allows it to download.
Now, be aware that all of your existing data, on the USB drive, will be deleted.
Since, I know that there isn't anything critical on that USB drive, I am willing to continue.
so
Partitions get deleted, a file system gets made...
and next, the operating system is copied over.
Now we can safely eject the flash drive.
And insert it into a computer, we wish to boot the OS from.
So, this is the laptop, we plan on installing Linux Mint to.
As you can see, this one has Windows 10 installed.
And it's not running really well.
This is why we're installing Linux Mint here.
now
Now, how do we boot from the flash drive?
If we insert the flash drive on to this computer.
We hear a ding.
And if we open my computer...
Then we see autoplay
And this is our USB, where we have
Linux Mint files.
which we use to boot
So, I'm going to show you the first method to...
...access your computer's SETUP program, because
which we can use to make it so that the computer doesn't boot from the internal drive, but instead from the flash drive.
For that we need to enter SETUP program.
There are 2 ways to do it. The first method...
If we hold...
We open power options in the start menu and see the option for Restart.
If we hold down the Shift key, which is the one under Caps Lock....
And click Restart.
We see a text that says "Please wait"
And we should soon see...
interesting stuff
so
here, if we go to Troubleshoot
Advanced options
UEFI firmware settings
And click Restart. Now for this laptop I have to do this...
And if we click "Restart"
Then our laptop goes to this "Startup Menu"
And from here we can choose "BIOS Setup"
And this is the SETUP program.
Now, let's assume this laptop doesn't have Windows installed.
I turned it off.
What's the second option?
For this laptop, I know that the key I should press is Escape.
And I think it also briefly shows to press Esc to interupt startup
That's the case for this laptop.
Your computer might be different.
Usually the key is either Delete or F2.
There may be other keys as well.
If you don't know the key, you can either use the first method I showed...
i.e. going to the advanced boot options and going into advanced options and selecting UEFI firmware settings.
Or refer to the motherboard instruction booklet.
So, let's use the Escape key method.
Let me turn it on.
And I'm going to repeatedly tap the Escape key.
Then we get to the same menu.
And here we can press F10.
To go to the boot options (I mean to say BIOS setup, sorry)
The first thing we want to find...
We have Boot options here.
aaaaaaaaaaand
okay, secure boot is disabled
now
To disable, we need to clear all secure boot keys.
So, that's the thing here.
Your computer might have a different setting for this.
then... since this isn't a legacy operating system...
Then we don't really care about Legacy Support.
We just want to clear secure boot keys.
I already did that, which is why it's showing the message.
And here we have boot order.
As you can see we have USB Diskette/Hard Disk set as first.
Here, it tells us that F5 and F6 keys move the options around, so if we do that...
it goes up or down
So, OS boot Manager is our internal storage
and operating systems we have there.
We can also make CD-ROM first
Like that. But that increases boot time, if we put unneeded stuff first in the boot order.
This laptop does not have a built in DVD drive.
So we don't neccessarily want to make it the first.
And if you are done, you can press Exit Saving Changes
And select Yes
And then your computer should automatically boot into the flash drive.
Once it decides to boot.
Okay
So, now we're in this menu.
This is what it looks like.
We have multiple choices here. We can just boot normally.
We can boot in compatibility mode.
Not 100% sure what that does.
OEM install is for when you want to install it to someone else's computer.
Boot from next volume
On this laptop, that option would just start Windows.
And UEFI Firmware Settings, like we saw in Windows.
Which also starts the SETUP program.
So, for this computer, we just want to boot normally.
And let's wait until we reach the desktop.
Which can take a few moments.
Now you should see the Linux Mint logo.
For some time.
Okay, we can see a mouse cursor.
I should mention that
the operating system might be a bit slower on the USB flash drive, than after installation.
Since I'm paranoid, I don't want Bluetooth to turn on automatically.
Can I just right click... yes.
We don't need Bluetooth right now.
One thing we should do.
Connect to our WiFi.
Now, it doesn't detect the 5GHz WiFi, because this laptop doesn't have the antennaes required for it, since it's so cheap.
So, I'm going to enter the password and be right back.
So, if you entered the correct password, you are connected, to the network.
Now you're in this live environment.
You can try various things here, for example to open a web browser.
Keep in mind that the USB is always going to be kind of slow, especially since this is a USB 2.0 flash drive.
We're going to open a familiar website...
Yes, we're connected to the internet.
This is the public version of my website.
And it works.
I think we're ready to install. So, just double click "Install Linux Mint".
Something is happening.
Okay, very good.
Perfect.
So, we're in this installation menu.
We can choose our language.
Let's scroll up a bit to find Estonian.
We can also read release notes.
Very cool.
Let's click "Next".
We can choose the keyboard layout.
Since we chose Estonian in the language option, it automatically chose the Estonian keyboard layout.
Here it asks if you want multimedia codecs.
This may be required to display videos and websites correctly.
Yes, let's turn it on.
why not
Even tough they are, yes, optional.
come back.
So
Now, here
We have a very important screen.
We can install Linux Mint alongside Windows.
We can format the drive and install Linux Mint.
Or we can do something else.
Now, if you don't want to lose your Windows install...
Then you can choose the first option, and I'll show what happens...
Let's select it.
Then it lets you set how big it is.
Due to space limitations, for this laptop, I would recommend the second option.
Plus, I don't really have anything on my Windows installation.
We can also do advanced stuff.
We can use ZFS if we want.
But if you want to use another file system, then you can choose something else here...
and do something else
Here are some tables and stuff.
I won't go into details for this one. For some reason I have Linux swap already.
Even tough I have Windows.
For simplicity, we are going to choose format disk and install Linux Mint.
Keep in mind this option erases everything
from your internal drive or hard disk, whichever you have.
Let's click "Begin installation".
And from here, it should notify us, that hey...
Have a look at what you are doing.
So, we are making two partitions. The first one is our ESP, i.e. UEFI partition.
And the second one uses the ext4 file system.
Which is a default on many Linux distributions.
Here we can choose our time zone. I'm just going to click Next here.
If it was incorrect, you could have just clicked on a spot on the map.
To see your time zone.
Here you can enter your details.
I have done some personalization here.
You can turn on automatic login if you want.
And encrypt your home folder, but then it has to ask your password.
Because why encrypt the folder, when you automatically log in?
And while we were setting it up, it was already copying some files
in the background.
And now we just wait.
While it's installing, we can see different features, Linux Mint offers.
Finding help is the last page.
I'll return once the installation has finished.
It should take 10-30 minutes, depending on the speed of your computer.
Once the installation is finished, you see this window.
Here you can choose to either continue the live session or restart now.
We are going to restart now to see what it does.
Of course, if you are doing something, you are free to continue the live session.
And then restart later.
Note that the flash drive is still plugged in.
And once it shuts down...
Then it should ask...
to please remove the installation medium, which we are going to do now.
And then press ENTER on your keyboard.
Which I somehow pressed.
Let's see if it...
What happens when the computer restarts...
We can see a bit of text.
And BOOM
IT'S A MINT!
And it connected to the WiFi network we setup before.
When you first boot, you can see various tutorials.
And first things you could do, for example...
choose your color scheme.
Make a system snapshot
Driver manager, if you have a Nvidia GPU for example...
Update manager, where you can do system updates.
Which is recommended.
The update manager has a new version available.
Let's install it.
And since this laptop is a bit slow, then...
I'm going to end recording this video.
And thank you for watching!