tl;dw MarkusTegelane in 2022
To understand today's video, we first need to talk about parallel universes.
Now the question is - what would you do in a parallel universe?
This operating system was designed for the x86 architecture.
But
But this tablet uses ARM architecture
For this, we are going to use the IBochs PC Emulator
Some smart people might say that this is Lunix, but that's not what it is.
It's not Lunix, it's actually Linux
Happy April Fools!
Next is Flood it, which is a game where...
you choose, which color to click on next.
And your goal is to get the whole thing to be the same color.
reboot
Does it eject the CD?
No
So, that was MultiROM.
This is basically a behind the scenes look.
To see what happens behind... behind
Next I want to talk about a batch file I'm working on.
It's called Draw Batch.
Registry keys. Now let's see what happens.
And boop.
wow
Okay, we have the default Windows 10 wallpapers.
Except for the one it's missing.
If we browse.
Let's see what what happens, right
Then it's Windows 10
So, you can play YouTube videos through VLC Media Player.
Is this some kind of paint?
It's some sort of a freeform drawing application.
What are those eyes?
Try to draw something yourself with a laptop touchpad.
So, we drew a very weird kite
a very weird man
and a weird balloon
wait
There's something wrong with this picture.
the wind man... wind man :D
The wind man with a portable black hole and a kite.
That's how I would describe it.
This bee won't stop lapping this man.
Why are these clouds moving so quickly?
The guy is dripping the plant.
Like, watering it, drop by drop, till the next century.
Oh, dog.
Are writing down all of the videos I've disliked?
So, the penguin said MOOOOOOOOOOOOOO
A very useful program, as you can see.
What if I told you... that MarkuStation... doesn't exist!
dislike.com
eaugh
Skelteon, where are you?
Where are you skeleton?
I want to knock you down.
okay
omg creeper
get out
Come here, creeper!
Come on! Come on! Yes, come on, creeper!
Come on! Come on!
Come here, creeper!
Come here! Come, Come, Come!
It didn't even drop gunpowder, what a scam.
Wait, there's no cooldown, I can just spam left click? No way!
I can just spam my axe, it's so OP.
Wait, is that a village.
Is that a village?
Or am I imagining things?
Or is it?
That is a village.
Definitely
Look, these are wooden houses.
Holy crap, we found a snow village!
We have food! YO, we have food! We can sleep!
dislike
uh oh
so... Google Chrome crashed.
Our memory usage hasn't increased a lot.
I am plugging in my tablet, because the battery might run out.
oh... how many? oh
2540 tabs.
I bet if we opened another 1000, Chrome would crash again.
It might even crash right now.. yup.
jinxed it
(some Google Translate non-sense)
blah blah restart
i guess
we have language, sessions
we can choose our session
gnome
xclient scripts
just for this ession
okay, that's KDE
is that KDE 4?
I think it is.
Who threw apple on the desktop?
In case you were unaware, my channel now has YouTube handles.
The name for my secondary channel has changed.
My long time viewers might remember a batch file called "The Chatroom"
The first video on my channel this year was a premiere episode of Markus computer entertainment season 2.
The community tab allows content creators to post text content, pictures and polls, in addition to the regular video content.
divorce
okay, I clapped
gnusmas dex is a desktop interface for gnusmas devices
anyway, let's talk about the technical details of this episode
hdmi hdmi
oh, I'm so good at this game
Guess what, they're showing ads!
I don't want ads!
/logo
2021, I think I did a bit more than just change the name for my channel.
I'm going to show you.
Basically, it's a keyboard and a cover combo
which costs way too much
We had a look at screen zoom. Wallpaper.
Let's enter the password.
If we enter a password, we're back.
It's pretty self-explanatory.
Contact us, what's that?
the irony
Next episode: Windows XP and more
A
Try re-installing Movie Maker
Hello! My name is reverse Markus
Happy
Go to the Linux Mint home page.
Click on Download
And you have 3 different version available
And the file is downloading.
While our OS is downloading...
It would a great idea to talk about a program
Rufus
And let's start Rufus.
Here, if we click on Troubleshoot
Advanced options
UEFI firmware settings
And then we click
And here we have boot order
As you can see, we have USB Diskette or USB Hard Disk set as first
Here we're told that F5 and F6 keys move it
should see Linux Mint Linux Mint
Okay, so after the installation is complete...
You have this window that pops up.
Where you can continue the live session.
Or restart now
This was a recap of the videos of the past year...
This year I didn't make a recap for all of my channels, because I posted enough videos on my main channel.
Happy new year('s eve)!