Hello, my I'm MarkusTegelane and welcome to another video!
For today's video, we're taking a look at an operating system that is on THIS flash drive!
*boop boop boop boop*
There's no...
The USB port is actually here
Wait, which side....
the USB plugged in
The problem is that I can't hold the camera and plug in a USB at the same time.
Okay
Let's see if it turns on!
Yay, we can select the boot device, let's choose F9
So... uaugh
WHERE'S THE FLASH DRIVE!?
WHERE'S THE FLASH DRIVE!??
we are experiencing technical difficulties
As it turns out, this laptop can only boot from one USB port, which is at the other side of the laptop.
ye
Now
If we turn it off and then back on...
This is so f___ing annoying
So, turn on!
Okay, Boot Device Options is F9
Le's a go!
And now, our thumb drive is finally f___ing visible!
So, secure boot disabled
What next?
Which operating system are we going to take a look at?
antiX is what MX is based on, so that's not very interesting
bodhi is just another ubuntu
debian
it's actually deepin
too demanding for this laptop
fedora is too good for this laptop
GParted is too boring
Haiku doesn't boot
I already made a video about Linux Mint
LXLE is too ugly
MakuluLinux...
I techincally already made a video about it.
But you can't find it. It's not on my channel yet, so...
*audience laughs at "is it arch? well yes, but actually no" linux*
MX Linux, already made a video about it.
neon is just KDE on Ubuntu
ponyos... what is PonyOS?
whawhawhat is this?
I think it's an operating system that's designed for dedicated horse fans.
Horses, they are interesting. Small horses are known as ponies, right.
Okay, why is there a heart?
Well, horses do hearts, right, and there aren't horses that don't have it
so I can kind of understand why is uses a heart as the boot screen
Why is it not loading?
But I do wonder, what does an operating made for horse fans look like?
I've seen several very interesting operating systems in my life.
Why aren't you booti-booting?
It booted last time I tried to do this!
Why are you not responding?
we are experiencing technical difficulties
Okay, I found a secret menu, where we can select the video mode!
Let's put it on the lowest resolution and see what happens.
okay okay
What does "Equestria font" mean? I have absolutely no idea.
I realized something tough. I should probably plug in a charger, maybe that's the issue we're having.
While searching for a charger, I found a DisplayPort cable.
. (nobody cares) .
yay
The charger has been plugged in!
boopboboo!
It's plugged in correct, very good.
Normal boots
Let's see what happens
that did not solve the problem
wow, I turned on my main computer
I'm going to enable legacy boot support
maybe then it's going to work better
Escape, escape, escablululululululululululululu...
escape escape escape escape eeer...
(relief sound)
BIOS Setup, that's F10
eeeergh F10
Very good. So...
Security....
Boot options, there we go!
Legacy Support
Enabled
Enter
Yes
whatever it was saying
Exit saving changes
yes
ESCAPE ESCAPE ESCAPE ESCAPE
so um, blururururururp, what did I do?
It booted onto the flash drive anyway
okay boot now
I'm not sure if legacy boot is enabled
the computer automatically booted in
UEFI mode, which is why it didn't work
Escape key, please work!
okay, blurrururururururp
F9
bopbopboop
did we select the...
Yeah, it booted using UEFI anyway, dang it!
So
Okay, now it's in BIOS mode, there we go!
oof
what is dis?
whatdefasfedf
didexkesu
But it's impossible to...
What key could you use to go into text mode?
text mode should be more usable
what key was it?
wait
arrow
NO!
NO, GO BACK!
GO BACK!!!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHAT ARE YUASHSFAD
ASFIOHASOIHGASPIHPIHGSAIOGAPOIGIOPSAG
HJ
we are experiencing technical difficulties
oh, that was... good!
Escape. Well
Okay, there we go. That's usable.
omg, ponyos.iso
Is it going to boot?
Press <Enter> to boot now
Okay ENTER ENTER
Well
Oh, hello!
eaarghmm
wtf is this?
uhm, okay
uhm
oh, wait a minute
That's not a pony!
Are you f___ing kidding? These are not f___ing ponies!
What the heck is this operating system?
Applications
Accessories
Where's the f___ing web browser?
It doesn't even come with a web browser!
uhm, next
Is it going to work?
This is a "Live CD". You can... make changes to the file system, blablablablah
uhm, okay
blah blah blah blah
blah blah blah
oof
Is there an option to install?
nop
This text is impossible to read!
I clicked on Julia fractals
If I tap the arrows, it changes the fractal.
Very exciting.
How large can I make it?
Weirdly enough, it didn't boot in UEFI mode.
No idea why.
It just didn't want to.
I have no idea what these things are on the desktop.
Whawhawhawhat is this desktop background?
uhm
readme dot markdown
provides a familiar Unix-like environment, but please be...
that the shell is incomplete and...
ehm
Why did I type 'led'?
ls
wow, it has ls
erghm
Does it come with apt?
Nope
pretty useless operating system
Are these all of the commands?
Why isn't ls on the list (the irony)?
Does it have man?
It doesn't even have man, like what?
So so garbage
oecho
hello
hecho helo
okokay that's a command
let's try something more fancy
keyboard, what
where's the $?
Okay, my phone storage is now full, so...
We'll have to deal with the fact I'm filming with my tablet.
So, a pretty useless terminal. What's packages?
What? It isn't 'ponyos'? Whawhawhawhat's the password then?
omg, I have to find...
BRUH
The password is 'local'.
okay
package manager, what's here?
index
Oh, I'm not connected to a network, that's why it's not working!
Select wallpaper.. what wallpapers does it come with?
wai what?
PONIES.JPG?
These things are f___ing ponies?
Are you kidding me? No, they're not ponies.
That's some kind of a joke.
Is that the only background?
Pretty flat.
alculator
A very useful... a very useful... application.
Is it just a calculator?
Well, obviously it's just a calculator
But is it a galculator?
oh, okay
Part of...
TOARUOS, WHICH IS FREE SOFTWARE RELEASED UNDER THE NCSA/UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS LICENSE
uhm, okay
What happens if we click on the web link?
Will it do anything (no it won't)?
nup
the sound isn't working
This OS barely f___ing runs on this laptop.
k
decorated, what's plasma, I really wanted to know
plasma
oh
fancy
This operating system apparently also has a website.
uhm
it has screenshots
wait, what the?
What command? ponysay?
okay
The 'ponysay' command.
what is this?
Bim? What?
Okay, for writing code and then there's an about dialog.
What's new?
New editor themes.
And it's 15 megabytes.
only
so...
This is where the password was, so...
very good
DOES PONYOS WORK ON REAL HARDWARE?
Yes, barely.
Is this really not a Linux distro?
No, doesn't seem like it.
"..does not include a compiler on the CD"
what
I want to compile stuff for my own...
Imagine me making my own program in PonyOS.
Wouldn't that be really horrible?
Can I put this on a bootable USB drive?
Turns out you can.
How do I mode windows?
You don't.
The problem is that my WiFi card wasn't detected, so R.I.P.
How do I install?
what?
"for your safety"?
*laugh*
For your safety, no we're not going to let you install it to your hard drive.
No, you can't upgrade.
That damn font is back, please can I turn it off?
Oh, you can do it from the bootloader men...
We did see that before, btw
Equestria font is... that font
A really good friggin font
What are people saying about PonyOS?
you have gone too far this time you...
very good reviews, as you can see, people are actually swearing at the OS
I'm not saying the end of that sentence.
I agree with this dude.
So, it's based on ToaruOS. What's that?
That looks like a normal operating system.
And they just put ponies on it.
I mean, imitations of ponies, because...
That is not a pony!
So, let's try that ponysay command.
so, here are all of the...
I typed 'ponysay -l' and here's everything I can put there.
for example...
okay
let's make it bigger
yup
Please send help!
The funny thing is that I'm making all of these characters call for help.
I assume these are the characters from that animation I don't remember the name of...
I think it's that weird animation this OS is inspired by.
I assume.
But I'm not 100% confident it's fro...
What is that clock?
what
what is that clock?
we can't do much, because we don't have internet
What is under undecorated?
Draw Lines
What is System Monitor, the only thing we haven't taken a look at?
It's like the performance tab on task manager
We can see how much resources are in use by our computer.
As you can see, this laptop doesn't have many cores.
How much memory does it use?
The memory usage is at 0 megabytes!
aaaj
network about
wow
I have a feeling we already saw that.
.taht was ydaerla ew gnileef a evah I
What is log out?
Are you sure you want to log out?
And then there's a person who's running.
They're probably running away from these pony imitations.
So, this is the login screen.
that font
username local, password loca...
*intimidation sound*
okay, so...
We entered the correct password.
I was looking at what this is, but it's like a plug going into a socket.
The last thing we can do... oh
The only option is log out, there's no shut down.
So as you can see, there's no escaping PonyOS.
I pressed the power button and nothing hap...
Oh, something did happen.
I had to press it twice!
Okay, escape escape escape!
I wanted to have a look at that Equestria font option
It was F7.
Better remember that.
Rectify11 seems interesting, but we have to finish the video on PonyOS instead.
Okay, let's untick this.
Oh, we have to press Enter, not the spacebar.
That's very weird, usually you press space to untick checkboxes.
Normal boot
What does this OS look like without that stupid font?
Okay, much more presentable.
Despite the fact this OS does not contain actual ponies
they're instead some kind of weird pony look-alikes
I do have to say, they've done a pretty good job
However, they could make a more useful operating system where the network card actually worked!
Yes, so that was
PonyOS. Thanks for watching!
Does the power button really...?
oh
anyway
Thanks for watching!
And till the next video!
Watch more