Hello!
In today's video I'm showing you how to flash a BIOS update using Asus EZFlash utility.
First of all...
Find your
computer or motherboard model number
And then visit the product support page for it
Then on this page
Download the BIOS
And save it somewhere on your flash drive
Next, extract files from the ZIP archive
Then safely eject the flash drive.
Now we're ready to flash the BIOS.
OK
Now, for flashing we're going to need a flash drive
a power adapter
if you're using a laptop
And then the computer itself.
Then open your laptop.
if you have a laptop
Then
plug in the flash drive
And connect the power adapter.
Make sure your power cable is connected
by checking that the indicator light is on.
Next, turn on the computer
and tap the F2 key.
Make sure your device has something like 50% battery.
That's in case when the power goes out.
Then select "Advanced mode". For this laptop, I have to press F7.
Go to advanced options menu.
select advanced
From here, choose ASUS EZ Flash 3 Utility.
Choose your flash drive
If you can't see your flash drive
Then try another USB port.
And exit EZ Flash.
And try again.
Now the flash drive is visible.
Choose the flash drive
and from here
I'm choosing
ASUS
video, then I'm choosing a file, which ends with a version number
Now it asks if you want to use that file
Select "Yes".
Give it a moment...
And here's some info about the BIOS version
Hit Enter to flash the BIOS.
And wait until the BIOS flashing is complete.
Don't turn off the computer during this process.
If you do turn it off, you won't be able to power it up again.
Be patient, this process may take a few minutes.
After flashing is complete, your computer will restart.
And as you can see, the new BIOS has been flashed.
Thank you for watching!