Are you tired of operating systems
such as Windows and Mac OS?
Do you want to decrease your productivity up to 100%?
Do you want your roommates to wake up due to blindingly bright light?
Then you should install Light Mode OS to your computer!
An operating system that just displays a white screen for eternity
I was walking in a forest at night.
and then
I realized I forgot my flashlight
But then I discovered I have a laptop
And when I booted it up...
Then it displayed a white screen and lit up the entire forest!
This operating system is total garbage.
Like, I don't get it. It just displays a white screen.
Like, I don't get why it exists.
Wait, was I supposed to say something positive?
Light Mode / OS
Get it today!
For floppy disks!
Only for 3 euros and 14 cents!
An amazing offer!
Exploit the chance today!
Because if you purchase a second copy
then you get a third one for free!
So, call 5
And get involved with this great offer!
Also visit our home page at