Okay, today we are destroying Windows Vista, everyone's favorite operating system.
Joy, it's running really well on my computer right now.
Let's make our Windows look a little bit better!
Am I the only one that did this sometimes?
like just max out the size
this theme looks really nice
just look at this preview, wtf?
yup
look at this preview
oh no
ok apply
oh no, what have I done?
Even the start menu isn't working properly
oh no
oh no, what did I do?
pole help us all
where did the taskbar go?
wtf, where are you going?
properties
that is checked, so I don't understand
oh, wait no
where are you disappearing?
Come back!
Let's search...
youtube.com
no thank you no thank you
okay... download... mediafire
Let's go!
install ok
ome moment, take snapshot
We're downloading weird stuff here, so...
oh my god
what have i done
extract to folder, okay
Access granted
lokibit dot com?
let's just click install and see what happens
2025 by the way
Simple version of program download video
Your download has started
Has it?
yes
continue
I agree
Installing toolbar files
hmmm
yeah yeah, why not
just install everything
oh yeah download
Is Opera advertising itself like this?
OperaSetup
Driver update, yeah yeah
Free download
download yeah yeah
Driver updater yes
open it
this one doesn't work as well, great
what a great... generative ai
okay
i'm male yes
i should have selected female, because it's technically correct
* reads stuff *
* keyboard typing sounds *
celsius female
finnish
let's make it bigger
nice
let's make it small again
and let's make it a background, there we go
ARE YOU SURE YOU WANT TO CANCEL?
yeah yeah
Is that what it was asking at one point?
submit
let's see if i'm smart
AAH
icy
Internet Explorer
EarthLink is here
Cannot display this page
great...
wtf happened?
What is going on with my computer?
* casually deleting important stuff *
What is the Boot folder? Doesn't seem important, let's delete it!
And now I think we can end csrss.exe
Yup, blue screen!
Enter
What do you mean you still start up?
they know... SOFTWARE, delete
Let's delete it
oh my god
but I think it already deleted a lot
SAM, who is SAM?
Wait, is this actually going to work?
no way
It's actually trying to delete it.
wtf
wait, can we draw?
we can't , unfortunately
A device attached to the system is not functioning.
fun
Network and sharing center
Windows DVD Maker, did that survive?
nup, everything... everything just falls apart
What's in the recycle bin?
nope
Windows Defender is turned off?
What do you mean?
Who turned off Windows Defender?
okay
Diagnose
Even diagnostics don't work.
This system is very broken.
You can't even click this button.
It's so broken.
oh no
Where are my programs? Oh no.
movie maker
nope
Movie Maker doesn't work.
Accessories
Wordpad
My last hope.
No, even Wordpad is gone.
Oh no.
cmd
cmd works, let's go!
ok
yay
I have to right click and.. WHAT?
Where's the "Run as administrator" option?
Task Manager
doesn't work
CTRL+ALT+DEL
CTRL+ALT+DEL does nothing
that's really good
CTRL+SHIFT+ESC opens system monitor on my host, but here it does nothing
oh... WHA WHA?
what is going on?
Why are we seeing a black screen?
Hellou?
Hallou?
hello?
It's probably crashed, let's just reset it, maybe that helps
* reading stuff *
Unexpected error has occurred.
Well, that's very descriptive.
Let's try safe mode, maybe that works.
nope, it does not
Command Prompt... no
Boot logging ... no
low resolution... no
Last known good configuration
wait a minute
will this actually boot?
NO
Last know good configuration... seems to have helped us.
oh no
No, it didn't!
wtf it blue screend!
welcome to finland
That's actually really funny. For a moment there I thought it was actually going towrok.
Directory Services Restore Mode, let's try that... no
debugging mode... nope
disable automatic restart... nope
disable driver signature... nope
start normally... nope
let's try again with last known good configuration
because it did get further
but if it now...
Does it get to the blue screen?
yup
it does blue screen
Replay:
The question is if we can fix this installation?
reset
Let's see if we can salvage this without fresh installing
ok
Searching for problems
It's trying to do something right now.
System restore
Let's see if that helps.
oh oh
oh, very nice
Okay, we seem to have completely bricked it.
Wait, but this is completely offline
yet there is an option to send information about this problem
let's see what happens
Can it even send the report if there's no internet?
* reads stuff *
rip
Advanced options
what can we do?
We can't really do anything useful apart from system restore, but I don't think it'll help.
bruh, it's not even starting
okay
we don't have that unfortunately
Memory diagnostics aren't really useful in this case
Startup repair didn't work
The only thing left is command prompt
Shut down
R.I.P. Windows Vista
You won't...
what? WHAT?
Replay:
WHAT?
What was the error message?