Markus Maal
Gettings things ready
Do not turn off the computer!
Error - everything intro is broken
Error - not connected
Markus's computer entertainment
Loading save save1...
MarkuStation
Licensed by
Markus entertainment Estonia
©MME
Starting from June 3rd, my channel will no longer be as active as it has been so far (1-2 videos per week). I probably won't upload new videos and I won't do that big of a transition to summer as I did last year...
Last year...
(X-files theme plays)
Markus Maal -
Connected
Connecting...
Couldn't connect 198.27.125.1
Markus Maal - Not
connected
Credits
Created by: Markus Maal
Music: Darude sandstorm
Pictures: From Google search
Thanks for watching
Press like, comment, and subscribe!
* Technical difficulties - Please stand by *
What the heck?
Lets do purple now!
* Technical difficulties - Please stand by *
You definitely can't read this text!
What the heck? *facepalm*
* Technical difficulties - Please stand by *
Markus Maal will no longer be making videos and that's the end of it!
* Technical difficulties - Please DO NOT stand by *